■
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译创作
最新最快的HR-HDTV 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译： zhanginfo  beatranslator  泥古拉斯  le_grand_bleu  icanHD
校对：进化的时间轴      监制：可乐嘻嘻      后期：LP_LadiesMan
休·杰克曼
铁甲 钢拳
别挂  别挂  来了
Hang on, hang on. Come on.
你在哪儿  查理  主要是我的钱在哪儿
Where are you, Charlie? More importantly, where is my money?
-你欠我三万块  -杰克  我正要还你呢
- You're into me for 30 grand. - Jack, I'm going to pay you.
我不是杰克  是比尔·帕纳
This ain't Jack! It's Bill Panner.
你还欠杰克钱吗  要先还我的
You owe Jack money, too? You pay me first!
比尔  没问题  咱是哥们  钱准备好了
Bill. We're good, buddy. I got your money.
就在我手上
It's right here in my hand.
我们在那什么地方见吧
Why don't we meet up on the?
-你电话断断续续的  喂  -我听不清楚
- Your phone's going all screwy. Hello? - I'm losing you.
你说什么  我听不到
I can't hear what you're say...
先生  那是伏击者吗
Hey, mister. Is that Ambush?
-没错  -我们能看看吗
- Yeah. - Can we see him?
-你们想看啊  -想
- You want to see him? - Yeah.
等一下啊
Give me a minute.
这位就是
This...
伏击者  起床啦
...is Ambush. Wakey, wakey.
-他要跟谁打  -眼下他要打的是
- What robot is he fighting? - Actually he's going to fight...
慢着小妹妹  你想干嘛
Whoa, little lady. What are you doing?
我们能和他合影吗
Can we get a picture with him?
行啊  先给五块钱
Sure. For five dollars.
要五块钱  开玩笑吧
You want five dollars? Seriously?
没开玩笑  现在就交
No, I want five dollars immediately.
咱还是走吧
Come on, guys.
-好好  逗你们呢  三块  -懒得理你
- All right, I'm kidding. Three bucks. - Whatever.
-两块五怎么样  -你穷疯了吧
- How about $2.50? - You suck!
又是个晦气的小地方
It's going to be one of those towns, huh?
女士们先生们
Welcome, ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎光临2020年圣莱安德罗乡村集市
to the 2020 San Leandro County Fair.
请大家就座
Please take your seats.
精彩节目即将上演
We're almost ready to get this thing started.
说好我的机器人斗的是八百磅的阉牛
I was told my bot was fighting an 800-pound steer.
那家伙可不止八百磅  你个白痴
That is not 800 pounds, knucklehead.
查理·"小超人"·肯顿
Charlie "The Can Do Kid" Kenton.
岁月催人老啊  朋友
Time has not been good to you, my friend.
里奇  这太不地道了
Ricky, we got a big problem here.
别激动啊  老兄
Slow down there, hoss.
上次见你时候
Last time I saw you, you were
还是在山姆休士顿中心被我一记右勾拳
staring at the ceiling at the Sam Houston Center
打得你四仰八叉  眼冒金星吧
with the taste of my right cross all over your face.
-还能不能开打了  -能啊
- Are we good to go here? - Yeah.
我们谈好我的拳手
We agreed that my boxer
跟八百磅的阉牛打  赢了我赚三千块
would fight an 800-pound steer for three grand.
-没错吧  -没错  谈好的
- Am I right? - Yes, sir. We did.
可那头牛大概有两千磅
That bull is like 2,000 pounds.
跟你这么说吧
I'll tell you something.
你那铁皮人不打  一个子儿也没有
Your bot don't fight, you don't get paid!
怎么样
How about that?
滚一边去
Get the hell out of here.
咱干嘛不玩儿大点
Why don't we make this more interesting.
让我机器人斗你的牛  拼个高下
My bot against your bull, straight up.
-赌多少  -两万  胜者全拿
- How much? - Twenty grand, winner takes all.
-两万你有吗  -车里锁着呢
- Twenty grand. You got 20 grand? - In a safe in my truck.
好吧  查理
All right, Charlie.
两万就两万  可万一你输了赖帐
Twenty grand it is, but if you lose and you welch,
我定会追到你天边  打到你半死
I'll come after you and beat you to within an inch of your life.
你知道我做得出来  因为我就这么干过
You know that I can do that because I already done it!
场外你还能唬唬人
In life you get too close,
一上场就怂得像个娘们  只会发抖
in the ring you stand back like a girl. Just shake.
没错  抖着就给你一拳
All right. Shake and pow!
跟上次那记一样  想再打一场吗
Just like that once again. You want to dance again?
给这家伙点掌声  给他来点运气
Cheer for this guy. Give him some luck.
各位  他缺的就是运气
He needs some luck, y'all.
别刺激那头牛
Don't touch that bull.
女士们  先生们  我要问一下
Ladies and gentlemen, I got to ask,
今天有想看机器人拳击的吗
do we have any fans of robot boxing here today?
听着朋友们  我知道不是谁都能
Now, listen, friends, I understand
千里迢迢赶往达拉斯
we can't all afford to go all the way over there to Dallas
花三百大洋观赏世界机器人拳联的赛事
and pay $300 for one of those World Robot Boxing League fights.
所以我决定在这里给诸位献上一场机器人拳赛
So, I decided that I would bring a robot boxing match
在我们圣莱安德罗这个小小集市上
right here to our little fair here in San Leandro.
要不要
How about that?
女士们  先生们  现在有请
Ladies and gentlemen, I introduce to you,
伏击者
Ambush!
开战吧
Let's do it!
好了吧  大块头
All right, big fella.
这家伙块头不小啊
He's a big fella, ain't he?
转个身  给观众看看你这雄伟身姿
Take a turn. Let them see how beautiful you are.
再展示展示力量
Show them some power.
看啊  还给我们表演功夫啊
Look at that. He's getting all kung fu-y on us.
好样的  大块头
Yeah, big fella.
伏击者今天的对手是
Ambush's opponent today, he's last year's runner-up
去年斗牛大赛的亚军
in the baddest of the bulls competition,
女士们先生们
ladies and gentlemen,
黑色霹雳
Black Thunder!
-比赛正式开始  -那就开打吧
- Let's get it on! - Let's get this thing started.
你就那点本事吗
Is that all you got?
这才对  老弟  来吧
Yeah, brother. Bring it on.
放倒它  放倒它
Take him, take him.
伏击者给蛮牛来了个大力抱摔
Ambush lays the smackdown on that prime beef.
咱招术多着呢  大块头  好戏还没开始
I got more for you, big fella. We're just getting started.
来个梯云纵  起
OK. Jump, now!
伏击者击倒了黑色霹雳
Ambush, decks Black Thunder,
一旦惹怒了公牛  两只利角可有你受的
but when you mess with the bull, you're going to get the horns.
喜欢吧  我知道你们喜欢这个
You like that. I can tell. You like that.
转身
Turn around!
里奇  里奇  快终止比赛
Ricky! Ricky, stop this thing!
起来啊  比赛还没完呢
Come on. We're still in this thing.
跳  用单足跳
Just hop. Hop.
就这样  冲上去
That's it. Come on.
里奇  行了  不能打了
Ricky, enough! Enough!
听不清  你那铁皮哥们被戳得太响了
I can't hear you over the sound of your robot being destroyed.
干掉他  干掉他
Kill! Kill! Kill!
快起来
Come on, get up.
起来啊  快起来
Get up! Come on!
不
No!
快呀  不  不要啊
Come on, no. No, no, no!
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
让我们为今天参加2020年圣莱安德罗乡村集市
let's hear it for our warriors out here today
的英勇斗士欢呼吧
at the 2020 San Leandro County Fair.
谢谢各位光临
Thank you for coming out,
下次再会  不见不散
and we'll see you next time, because there will be one.
把腿还我
Give me that leg.
好啊  五块钱
Sure. For five dollars.
看你再拽
Boo-yah!
好了  多么欢乐的赛事啊
All right! That was ridonculous fun,
是不是啊  各位
now wasn't it, ladies and gentlemen?
我这就来要钱了  查理老兄  最好你有
I'm going to come by for my money, Charlie boy. You best have it.
-大家嗨起来  -嗨
- Everybody say "Hey!" - Hey!
-大家再吁起来  -吁
- Everybody say "Ho!" - Ho!
怎么样  爽不爽  铁皮人
How about that? How you doing there, little robot?
钥匙呢  妈的
My keys, damn it.
再过来就把你像娘们一样搞趴下
One more step and I'll drop you like your girlfriend.
查理  别激动
Charlie, relax.
我不会掏钱的  比赛作弊
I'm not paying you. That was a bogus fight.
还搭上了我最后一个机器人
It cost me my last robot.
-听我们说  -记着卡罗琳·法伦吗
- Just listen to us. - Do you recall Caroline Fallon?
我前女友
She's my ex-girlfriend. I
我十年没见她了  她想怎样
haven't seen her in ten years. What does she want?
不怎样  她去世了
Nothing. She died.
你记着麦克斯·肯顿
Do you recall Max Kenton?
我儿子  该有九岁了吧
He's my son. He's got to be nine.
-十一岁  -都十一了
- Eleven. - Eleven. OK.
他也死了吗
Is he dead, too?
没  他很好  所以我们才来找你
No, he's fine. That's why we're here.
本庭拟审理名叫麦克斯·肯顿的11岁男童
This court is convened to address the custodial status
之监护权问题
of one Max Kenton, age 11.
其母卡罗琳·法伦已故  其父是查尔斯·肯顿
Mother, Caroline Fallon, deceased. Father, Charles Kenton.
黛布拉·法伦·巴恩斯  你是其姨妈
Debra Fallon Barnes, you're the boy's aunt.
是  如前所述  我先生马文家道殷实
Yes. As I've already told you, my husband, Marvin, is wealthy,
麦克斯可以获得更好的抚养
and we can more than provide for Max.
对此我表示理解  但依据德州法律
I appreciate that, but per Texas state law,
如没有书面遗嘱
without a written will
其最近血亲将保有监护权
next of kin retains custody.
就是查尔斯·肯顿  他已被告知此次聆讯
Charles Kenton, who is aware of this custody hearing,
我们正等他出席
and we are expecting him...
我现在需要一个新机器人
I need a new robot now.
下周六我给伏击者安排了场恶战
I had a big fight for Ambush next Saturday.
我总得找一个代替他啊
I got to show up with something.
超恶男子要卖吗  想当年他可无人能敌
Noisy Boy is for sale? In his day, Noisy Boy was a killer.
多少钱  很划算  他有什么毛病吗
How much? That's a good deal. What's wrong with him?
那不是问题
I can live with that.
我现在没钱
I don't have it.
从孩子一出生查尔斯·肯顿
Charles Kenton waived all of his
就放弃了监护权
rights to custody right after the boy was born.
我更有条件抚养麦克斯
I can more than provide for Max.
你是查尔斯·肯顿
Please be Charles Kenton.
对  查理
Charlie, yeah.
我来这里签署文件
I'm here to sign some paper that releases my rights
放弃儿子的监护权
to the custody of my son.
就为这个  怎么我不用来吗
That's why I'm here. Do I need to be here?
查理
Charlie.
还记得我吗
Do you even remember me?
黛布拉  卡罗琳的妹妹
Debra, Caroline's sister.
对  黛布拉  你好
Yeah, Debra. How are you?
肯顿先生  请就座
Mr. Kenton. Please take a seat.
法官大人  我可以去看看我外甥吗
Your Honor, may I please go and see my nephew now?
你可以去
Yes, you may.
-肯顿先生  你呢  -我什么
- How about you, Mr. Kenton? - What?
你要是愿意  可以去陪陪孩子
You can spend some time with him, if you'd like.
-陪孩子?  -对  陪孩子
- With the kid? - Yeah, the kid.
-麦克斯  你亲儿子  -行行
- Max. Your son? - All right.
看你是跟机器人混太久了
You've been working with
也成铁石心肠了
those robots for so long, you've become one.
亲爱的  在这里等一下  我去去就来
Honey, you wait right here. I'm going to be back.
宝贝  你愿意多久都可以的
You take all the time you need, sweetheart.
法官大人  我想趁这个时间
Your Honor, I'd like to, at this juncture,
出去给律师打个电话  可以吗
step out and call my attorney, if that's all right.
请便
Please.
快点  出来啊  总算来了
Come on. Come on. There you are.
他会住在寄养家庭
He'll be in a foster home.
没事  他们给挑好人家
No, they find good families.
年轻有为的  对
Young. Energetic. Yeah.
谢谢  迈克尔  我会的  好
Thanks, Michael. I will. OK.
-马文·巴恩斯  黛布拉的先生  -哦对
- Marvin Barnes. I'm Debra's husband. - Right, yeah.
黛布拉很希望抚养麦克斯
Debra really wants to adopt Max.
-我也有此意  不过...  -七万五
- I'm up for it. But... - Seventy-five grand.
七万五千美金  你认真的?
$75,000? You're serious?
问题是...
The thing is...
今年夏天我们计划好去意大利
...we're supposed to go to Italy this summer
和我朋友他们夫妇俩
with my oldest friend and his wife.
在托斯卡纳等地待两个月
Two months in Tuscany and all over.
就你们四个  真不错
Just the four of you. Sounds nice.
到八月底我们再回纽约
We'll be back in New York by the end of August.
八月?  那十万
In August. A hundred.
-十万块  -没错
- $100,000? - You heard me.
-你真疯了  -没你太太疯
- You're crazy. - Not nearly as crazy as your wife
要是我告诉她同意
if you tell her I just
让德州政府接管孩子  那她才会疯呢
signed over that kid to the state of Texas.
这是个让大家都满意的好办法
There's a real way everyone gets what they want here.
所以教你怎么做
So here's what you're going to do.
跟你太太说  先让我陪孩子一夏天
You're going to tell your wife I'll only sign over custody to her
然后我就签文件  把监护权交给她
if I get to spend the summer with the kid first.
告诉她  作为一个没管过孩子的糟糕父亲
Just tell her how guilty she made me feel
她让我觉得自己有多愧疚
for being such a terrible absentee dad,
我又是多想陪陪小家伙
how I want to make good with junior,
重塑父子之情什么的
a little fatherly bonding, whatnot.
她肯定买账  你当你的英雄  人人满意
She'll buy it, you get to be the hero and everybody wins.
好  但钱的事不许和黛布拉提  明白吗
OK. But not a word about the money to Debra, you understand?
当然明白
I understand.
今晚把麦克斯交给你时先付五万
I'll give you 50 grand tonight when we drop off Max
另外五万等我们八月份回来
and the other 50 when we get back in August
你把他送到纽约后给你
and you deliver him to us in New York.
合作愉快
Pleasure doing business with you.
法官大人  很高兴大家抽出时间
Your Honor, I'm happy we all took the time
达成人人满意的最佳结果
to make the best decision for everyone.
-开心吗  -喂  是我
- Happy? - Yeah, it's me.
我要买超恶男子  钱搞定了
I'm buying Noisy Boy. I got the money.
把他运到塔立拳房  那里见
Take him to Tallet's Gym and I'll meet you there.
在吗
Hello?
贝莉
Bailey?
有人把你买的机器人送来了
Some guy is here with the robot you're buying,
查理  我敢说它不是什么好东西
and I'm gonna tell you, Charlie, it smells like disaster to me.
我也很高兴见到你
Nice to see you, too.
-也许还应该说你真可爱  -算了吧
- Might I also say how cute you look. - Give it up.
老天  我得冲个凉  要一起来吗  来吧
God, I need a shower. You want to take a shower? Come on.
跟你说清楚
Let me make something clear.
来送机器人那个神经病
A creepy dude with a robot in a box
在我拳房外已经坐了两个钟头
has been sitting outside my gym for two hours.
先不说你在我店门口搞的这勾当
Putting aside the fact that you're doing
我猜也是非法交易
what I'm guessing is a black market deal on my doorstep,
就说说你打算怎么付这钱
how will you pay him
现在伏击者也毁了
when Ambush just got destroyed?
钱马上到  先拖住他
The money is on its way. Just distract him.
试过了  费劲死了
I have been. It's exhausting.
-你人最好了  -是吗  真的吗
- You're the best. - Yeah? Really?
于是你能花四万五买个机器人
Is that why you're buying a $45,000
却欠我六千租金不还吗
robot when you owe me six grand in rent?
-就因为我人好吗  -三千吧
- Because I'm the best? - Three.
六千  有人真金白银想买我这地方
Six. There is a guy with real money who wants to buy this place.
得了  说得像你真会把你爸拳房卖了似的
Come on. Like you're really going to sell your dad's gym.
要是你不给租金
If you don't make rent, I
我怎么生活  我没得选择
can't make payments and I won't have a choice.
要是你把这地方卖了
Your father would climb out of his grave and kick your ass
你爸非从坟墓里爬出来揍你
if you sold this place.
我爸要是爬出坟墓
My father would climb out of his grave
也是揍你
and kick your ass.
贝莉
Bailey?
-你别  -别什么
- Don't. - Don't what?
别这样
Don't do that.
-别怎样  -别这么盯着我
- Don't what? - Don't do that thing.
-不  你喜欢我这样  -不喜欢
- No, you like that thing. - No.
-喜欢  -不  我不喜欢你这样
- Yeah. - No, I don't like that thing.
曾经喜欢  过去了
I used to. Once.
说白了我现在更喜欢钱
Briefly. Now I like money more.
-我不信  -随便你
- I don't believe you. - I don't care.
马文
Marvin.
钱说来就来了
Your money has arrived.
老马
Marv.
五万  说好的
Fifty grand, as promised.
这是我们在欧洲所有的电话和联系方式
Here are all our numbers and contact info over in Europe.
都在里面
So that's everything there.
马文告诉我这段时间你想陪陪麦克斯
So Marvin tells me you want this time with Max.
是的
Yeah.
把监护权交给我是正确的选择
You did the right thing, giving me custody.
卡罗琳一定也希望如此
Caroline would have wanted that.
那就  八月二十七号给我们送到纽约
Now, have him back in New York on August 27th.
放心吧
That's a deal.
那我们去找麦克斯好吗  去叫麦克斯
OK, let's go get Max. OK? Let's get Max.
没问题的
It's OK.
要么你到车那边去  我来叫麦克斯出来
You want to go around the other side here and I'll get Max?
麦克斯  再见  小伙子
Hey. Max. See you, pal.
麦克斯  宝贝  夏天一过我们就能见面了
Max, we'll see you at the end of the summer, honey.
我是查理
I'm Charlie.
好久不见了  你也知道  我是你
It's been a long time. You know, I'm your...
-你害惨我了  -小嘴还挺厉害
- You screwed me. - Nice mouth.
你知道他们要去哪儿吗
Do you know where they're going?
-意大利吧  -对  意大利
- Italy? - Yeah, Italy.
那我干嘛要跟着你瞎混
So how did I get stuck here with you?
孩子别急  以后你好日子过都过不完
Relax, kid. You got a whole life of fine living ahead of you.
查理
Charlie!
那家伙毛了  准备走人了
Dude's pissed. He's going to take off.
是马文给你的钱吗
Did Marvin give you that money?
给  赶紧把钱结了
Here, just close the deal.
我马上就过去
I'll be right there, OK?
-我叫贝莉  -麦克斯
- I'm Bailey. - Max.
麦克斯·肯顿
Max Kenton.
-这就是你  -对  是他
- So this is your... - Yeah, it's him.
这你甭管了  好吗
Don't worry about it, OK?
我看你们俩还真是
I'm looking at you two and...
赶紧过去把超恶男卸进去吧  多谢了
Just go and put Noisy in the shop, please? Thank you.
我出去时候你就跟她待在这里
You're going to stay here with her while I'm on the road.
他给你多少
How much did he give you?
你想歪了
You're coming at this the wrong way.
不  告诉我  我想知道
No, tell me. I want to know.
五万  好了吧
Fifty thousand, OK?
他给我五万  我把监护权交给她
He gave me $50,000 to sign you over to her.
现在可以闭嘴了吗
Will you shut up now?
你把我卖了
You sold me?
干嘛说这么难听啊
Sounds worse than it is.
-难听吗  -都是为了照顾你
- Really. - It's to take care of you.
钱分我一半  我不用你照顾
Give me half the money and you won't have to.
-你想去哪儿  -给我钱  不用管我
- Where are you going to go? - Give me the money. I'll be fine.
我和你姨妈说
I told your aunt I'll get
夏天过了就把你送回纽约
you to New York at the end of the summer.
你还会为黛布拉姨妈考虑吗
Now you're concerned for Aunt Debra?
五万块你把我卖了  你欠我一半
You sold me for 50 grand. You owe me half!
没了  我买了个机器人
I don't have it! I spent
花光了  好了吗  一分不剩
the money on a robot. It's gone! OK? Gone!
我进店去了
I'm through here.
看看货吧
What do we got?
有请超恶男子
Noisy Boy has arrived.
空运贴纸和海关标签还不少啊
That's a lot of airline stickers and customs tags.
他简直周游了趟世界
He's been all over the world.
伦敦  日本  巴西  圣保罗
London, Japan, Brazil, Sao Paulo...
两年多没踏上过北美大陆
Hasn't seen North American soil in over two years.
也许因为这样才这么便宜  算你厉害
Maybe that's why you got such a good price, genius.
决定留下了吗
Decided to stay?
这是贝莉  她会照顾你几个星期
This is Bailey. She'll be looking after you for a few weeks.
对了  你得帮我照顾他几个星期
Oh, by the way, I need you to look after the kid for a few weeks.
-我要分一半的钱  -怎么又扯回来了
- I want half that money. - Are we back to this again?
里面是真的机器人拳手吗
Is there a real robot boxer in there?
超恶男子在里面  听说过吗
Noisy Boy's in there. You ever heard of him?
当然
Of course.
他曾和卢比肯争夺2016年世界机器人拳击大赛
He fought Rubicon for the WRB belt in 2016.
天啊  太帅了
Holy crap, he looks amazing.
他的复合装甲都换过了
His composite armor has been replaced.
看看内部是不是一样好
Let's see if the insides look as good.
他和卢比肯那场比赛我看了二十几遍
I've watched that fight with Rubicon like 20 times.
本来第三轮就应该拿下的
He should have had him in the third round,
可卢比肯右手碰巧击出一记重拳  结束了
but Rubicon got lucky with a huge right and ended it.
别怕  孩子  他是自己人
Relax, kid, he's on our side.
-不好笑  -还行吧
- Not funny. - Kind of funny.
你知道它有声音识别功能吧
You know he has voice recognition, right?
-不  它没有  -它不参加联赛了
- No, he doesn't. - He didn't in the League.
超恶男在巴西打斗时  他们肯定给它装上了
When Noisy fought in Brazil, they must have put it in.
巴西人非常热衷于和机器人讲话
Brazilians are crazy about that talk-to-your-robot crap.
右拳  左拳  上钩拳
Right, left, uppercut!
不管用  右拳  左拳  上钩拳
Doesn't work. Right, left, uppercut!
我就知道便宜没好货  我们上当了
I knew that price was too good to be true. We got screwed.
-我看看能不能修  -样子货
- Let me see if I can fix it. - Look how good he looks, too.
给我点时间  我来看看是什么问题
Give me two seconds. Let me look at something!
-你为什么不要求检查检查它  -放松点
- Why didn't you ask to look at it? - Relax!
你说的是日语吗
Was that Japanese?
我看看能不能把它设置成英语模式
Let me see if I can reset him to English.
你怎么会日语
How do you know Japanese?
从电动游戏中学来的
Video games.
你用日语玩电动游戏
You play video games in Japanese?
走私的日本游戏都比较好
Japanese bootlegs are always better.
给我
Give me that.
把它设置成英语了
He's reset to English,
我还找到了他的命令模式
and I found his command matrix.
他们预装了一系列的组合拳
They have pre-loaded a bunch of combinations.
应该就列在这里
They should be listed here.
顶部齐射
Top salvo!
我不是吹牛吧
What did I tell you?
重拳三合一
Gravity One Downtown!
好运总是姗姗来迟
I was due for some good luck!
-不客气  -谢谢你
- You're welcome. - Thank you.
贝莉  帮我把它运上卡车
Bailey, help me put him in the truck.
我去给你赚点钱
I am going to go and get your money.
-给我钥匙  -我要和你一起去
- Give me the keys. - I'm coming with you.
-不  不行  -为什么
- No, you're not. - Why not?
因为我不想让你和我一起去
Because I don't want you with me, OK?
要么我和你一起去
I'm either coming with you,
要么你就到下水道里去找你的钥匙
or you're fishing for your keys in the sewer.
你选择吧  你会怎么选  老家伙
Your choice. What's it going to be, old man?
天哪  差点就掉了
Oh, my God. That was close, wasn't it?
-别再那么做了  -吓坏你了  不是吗
- Don't do that again. - That's scaring you, isn't it?
不要再这么做
Don't do this again?
上车  赶紧上车  先把钥匙给我
Get in. Just get in. Give me the keys first.
我上了卡车再给你  谢谢  老爹
Wait till I get in the truck. Thanks, Big Pops.
很舒适
Sweet ride.
戴上安全带  闭嘴
Put on your seatbelt and don't talk.
撞击宫殿
我全押上
I'm taking all bets!
跟紧  别落下
Keep up. Stay close.
查理·肯顿来了
Charlie Kenton is in the house!
-好了  好了  -过来  伙计
- All right, all right. - Come on, man!
-那是超恶男子吗  -世上唯一仅有的
- Is that Noisy Boy? - The one and only.
那是超恶男子
That's Noisy Boy!
超恶男去过日本  那边的机器人都比较差劲
Noisy's been in Japan. Softer bots over there.
-你确定让他今晚打斗吗  -你下什么赌注
- Sure you want to fight him tonight? - What do you got?
他可以拿下这里任何一个机器人  你了解的
He can take any bot in this place. You know it.
你可以选任何一个对手
You can have any undercard you want.
五千元的保证金
Five thousand guaranteed.
你的机器人打赢一轮就得一千元
A thousand every round your bot survives.
直到打趴下
Fight till the death!
不  我要打主赛场
No. Give me the main event.
-得了  -这可是超恶男子
- Come on. - This is Noisy Boy.
一个原装达克·马西多的机器人
An original Tak Mashido bot.
他曾是一名世界级的机器人联赛拳击手
He was a World Robot League boxer. Come on!
你想和迈达斯打斗
You want to fight Midas?
五万元保证金  赢家全拿
Fifty thousand guaranteed, winner takes all.
五万元  真的吗  五万  这才像样
Fifty? Really, 50? Now you're talking.
听我说  不行
Listen, listen. No, look.
-听我说  -等我一下
- Listen! - Give me a sec.
前导比赛:在正式拳击比赛之前的垫场赛
我们应该参加前导比赛
We should take an undercard fight,
赚点钱然后离开这里
make a little cash and get out of here!
首先  这里没有"我们"
First, there is no "We."
其次  他会把迈达斯打得片甲不留
Second, he's going to crush Midas,
我会大赚一笔
and I'm going to make real cash!
我们要挑战迈达斯
We'll take Midas!
今晚  我们的主赛场
Tonight, our main event
呈现金色血性杀手
features the gold-blooded killer!
这个皮条朋克
This pimped-out punk
为痛苦出演
is programmed for pain!
有请威武的迈达斯
I give to you the mighty Midas!
对决的机器人
Against a bot
曾在大赛中与重量级的机器人交锋
who ran with the big boys in the WRB!
它曾流放海外  但是现在凯旋而归
He's been on an exile tour overseas, but now he's back home,
准备大造声势
and he's ready to make some noise!
请对超恶男子
Take your first look in a long time
投以注目吧
at Noisy Boy!
撞击宫殿
Crash Palace,
准备好毁灭了吗
who's ready for some destruction?!
我们来赚钱吧
Let's make some money! Come on!
现在迈达斯对决超恶男子
We have Midas against Noisy Boy.
超恶男子对决迈达斯
Noisy Boy against Midas.
你们为这场比赛等了整晚  撞击宫殿
You've been waiting all night for this matchup, Crash Palace!
右拳短弯刀
Scimitar right!
你们看见了吗
Did you see that?
哗哗地赚钱  整晚哗哗地赚钱  整整一晚
Easy money, easy money all night. All night long!
加油  比赛还没结束  我们上
Come on! It's not over yet. Let's go!
勾拳向上  重拳出击
Skull salvo! Firefight!
-好样的  上  超恶男  -前导比赛?
- Yeah! Go, Noisy! - Undercard, huh?
重拳击
Shockfist!
贴近打  大将军三拳一体
Get in there. Shogun Trinity!
打跨它  重拳击  直击
Let's finish him. Gravity Slam, Uptown!
这婊子疯了
This son-of-a-bitch is crazy!
全力复仇  上啊
Full Metal Feud! Bring it!
左拳  努力回转
Southpaw! Pain Revolution!
我给你来个厉害的
I got something for you.
看你还怎么逃走  你逃不了了
Don't you run from me! You can't run from me!
站起来
Get up!
这不合法
That's illegal!
这里是地下拳赛  没有规则
This is the underworld. There are no rules!
现在我看到迈达斯在回击
Now we're seeing the Midas touch.
不  用你的拳头
No. Hands up!
回到那个角落
Get back in that corner,
贱人  高声叫起来  像个男子汉
bitch, and take this whooping like a man!
他会被杀死的
He's getting killed in there!
这是耳机  你告诉他怎么做
It's a headset! You talk into it and you tell him what to do!
恐慌盾牌
Panic Shield!
对了  一二霸王拳
That's it. One-Two Overlord!
不  不  捣毁拳
No, no. Shatter Punch!
-五连击  -吃这一拳
- Five Recall! - Get some!
猛击  猛击
Jab, jab!
右臂大弧度挥臂
Right roundhouse!
它刚刚是吐了迈达斯一脸油吗
Did he just spit his juice in Midas's face?
不  你没有吐迈达斯一脸油
No, you did not spit in Midas's face!
现在狂欢时间  撞击宫殿
It's party time now, Crash Palace!
用左拳
Use your left!
超恶男试图用一只胳膊力挽狂澜
Noisy's trying to do something with his one arm!
但是迈达斯先下手为强  老家伙要努力
But Midas pins him, and Daddy goes to work!
不  不  起来
No, no! Get up!
受死吧
Get some!
动起来  离开角落
Move! Get out of the corner!
迈达斯  迈达斯  迈达斯
Midas! Midas! Midas!
有人准备送上一杯低因咖啡了
Somebody's ready to serve up a decappuccino!
我有更厉害的一招  你准备好吗
I got something for you! You ready?
晚安  迈达斯全垒打
Good night! That's a home run for Midas.
再见了超恶男子
And so long to Noisy Boy.
真窝囊  你饿了吗
That sucked. You hungry?
我保留了超恶男的声音识别板
I saved what's left of Noisy's voice recognition board.
除了那个  它就是块垃圾了
Other than that, he's trash.
我得再整合一个新的机器人
I got to get a new robot together.
我需要找一个主机  怎么了
I need to find a mainframe. What?
我不喜欢汉堡包
I hate hamburgers.
什么样的孩子会不喜欢汉堡包
What kid hates burgers?
好吧  我吃  你喝这个
Fine. More for me. Here, drink this.
你本不该参加那场打斗
You never should have taken that fight.
真的吗  真的吗  谢谢  天才
Really? Really? Thanks, genius.
你做事前有没有动过脑子
Do you even think about the stuff you do before you do it?
你根本都不知道怎么去打斗
You had no idea how to fight that fight.
你对那些组合拳码
Those combination codes,
连一半的含义都不明白
you didn't know what half of them even meant.
你狂妄自大毫无计划地把让它们抛弃
You threw them in there cocky and half-assed.
你从来没有给过它一次机会
You never gave him a chance.
他并没有那么棒
He wasn't that good.
超恶男子是个很棒的机器人
Noisy Boy was a great robot.
曾经  它曾经在联赛里是个很棒的机器人
Was. Was a great robot back in the League,
时过境迁
back in the day.
但是看看你周围
But look around you.
这是那些伟大的机器人死去的地方
This place is where once great robots go to die.
所以就把它扔掉
So throw him away.
这是你的一贯作风  对吗
That's what you do, right?
一旦没有利用价值了  你就将之抛弃
Anything you don't need you throw away.
真是漫漫长夜
It's been a long night.
如果你今晚想睡在屋里
If you want to sleep indoors tonight,
就闭上嘴上车
shut up and get in the truck.
别用那种眼神看我  赶紧上车
Don't look at me like that way. Get in the truck!
它的头卖了四百块
They gave me 400 for his head.
你留在这里别动  我去看看别的零件
You stay put. I'm going to look for parts.
我和你一起去  这饮料让我的心咚咚跳
I'm coming with you. That drink has my heart pounding.
如果我自己待在车里  头会炸掉
If I sit in this truck by myself, my head will explode.
随便你  跟紧点
Whatever. Just keep up.
该死
Crap.
退后
Stay back.
跟紧点
All right, keep up.
这些探照灯是自动的  但是你得计算好时间
These searchlights are automated, but you got to time them right,
所以跟紧点
so stay close.
好了
It's all right.
快点  快点
Come on, come on.
-我们会被抓住的  -快点
- We're going to get caught. - Come on.
慢点  慢点  慢点  慢点
Easy, easy. Easy, easy.
快  快  蹲下来  走  走  走
Quick, quick. Down in here! Go, go, go!
机器人都在东面  我们得赶紧
Robots are on the east side. We got to be quick in here.
过了这里就没有探照灯了  快  走
Once we're through here, there's no more searchlights. Quick! Go!
-到了  -我们在找什么
- Here it is. - What are we looking for?
我可以用来组装打斗机器人的东西
Anything I could use to put a fighting bot together.
-看  -什么
- Hey, look. - What?
这么小
It's so small.
是的  它比你年龄还大
Yeah. That's before your time.
那是第一代  第一代打斗机器人
That's a Generation One, the very first fighting bot.
他们希望机器人看起来像人类  越像越好
They wanted them to look like us. The more human, the better.
真是时过境迁
Crazy how quick everything changed.
把那个放在手推车上
Put that in the cart.
-什么变化  -很好的问题  人类拳击
- What changed? - A good question. Human boxing.
-就这么衰落了  -为什么
- It just faded. - Why?
因为钱的驱使
Because the money moved on.
大家想看更多的残杀  更血腥的表演
People wanted more carnage, more show.
巴西人的地下组织汇集了一切
You had the whole Brazilian underground,
格雷西  马沙杜
the Gracies, the Machados,
柔道  泰拳  在这中间有上千种种类
jiu-jitsu, Muay Thai, and a thousand styles in between.
五花八门的拳击
Full-on ground-and-pound.
-看这个  -那是什么
- Look at this. - What's that?
我不知道
I don't know.
还不错  很好的零件
Not bad. Good spot.
仍然是人类拳击  人类的身体
You still had human fighters, human bodies,
你就不能带给大家他们所期待的东西
so you couldn't give the people what they really wanted:
那种身临其境的  无拘无束的暴力
True, no-holds-barred violence.
下一个合理的推进
The next logical step,
就是让人类退出  让机器人彼此残杀
get the humans out of there and let the machines kill each other.
你怀念以前吗
Do you miss it?
-拳击  你怀念吗  -当心
- Boxing. Do you miss it? - Careful.
什么  我想知道
What? I want to know.
当心  你在悬崖边上了
Careful, you're on a cliff.
下面很深  如果你摔下去了  你一定会
That's a long way down. If you fell, you'd definitely...
查理  救救我
Charlie, help me!
查理
Charlie!
-查理  -麦克斯  麦克斯
- Charlie! - Max! Max!
麦克斯
Max!
-不要动  -一个机器人的手抓住了我
- Try not to move! - I'm on some sort of robot arm.
等等  放松  把手给我  慢慢地给我
Wait! Just easy, easy. Give me your hand. Nice and easy.
非常慢  很好  别向下看  看着我
Very slowly. Good. Don't look down. Look at me. Look at me.
就是这样  我抓到你了  你不要害怕
That's it! I've got you! You don't have to be scared.
我抓住你了
I got you!
-还很远  -没关系  我抓住你了
- It's so far! - It's OK. I got you.
把另外一只手给我  慢点
Give me your other hand. Nice and slow.
慢慢地把你另外一只手给我
Just give me your other hand very slowly.
往回伸  使劲伸
Reach back. Come on. Reach!
看着我  我们一起共渡难关
Look at me. We're going to do this together.
你和我  看着我  就是这样
You and me. Just look at me. That's it.
一  二  三
One... two... three!
就是这样  我抓住你了  我抓住你了
That's it. I got you! I got you. I got you. I got you.
你安全了  你安全了
You're safe. You're safe.
我抓住你了
All right, I got you.
-你还好吗  -很好
- You all right? - Yeah.
过来  放轻松  放轻松
Come here. Easy. Easy.
你还好吗
You all right?
-你还好吗  -没事
- You all right? - Yeah.
我告诉过你这里很危险
I told you it was dangerous.
当心点  我们还在悬崖边上
Careful. We're still on the edge here.
查理  我觉得这里有一个完整的机器人
Charlie, I think there's a whole robot in there.
那又怎么样  我们走  快点
So what? Let's go. Come on.
我要带上他  他救了我的命
I'm taking him with me. He saved my life.
他没有救你的命  我救了你的命  我们走
He did not save your life. I saved your life. Let's go.
把推手带过来
Just bring the cart to the edge.
我要用绞盘把它拉出来
I'll use the winch to get him out.
你想要一堆垃圾
You want that piece of junk?
你自己去推车  我要离开这里了
You get the cart yourself. I'm through here.
这就是超恶男子的残骸了吗
This is what's left of Noisy Boy?
对
That's it.
他的头给撞击宫殿的前门
His head does make a nice addition
当装潢了
to the front of the Crash Palace.
-这并不可笑  -我们再做一个机器人
- It's not funny. - Let's get a robot, you and me.
好主意  你破产了  我也快了
Good idea. You're broke. I'm almost there myself.
你毁掉了了最好的的一次机会
You destroyed the best shot you had.
我们可以再建一个
We'll put one together.
你在这方面很有才华  这里有很好的材料
You're brilliant at this. There's good stuff here.
-这里什么也没有  -这里  看
- There's nothing here. - There is. Look.
这些只是些垃圾  垃圾
All your junk is... it's junk.
你甚至都不能再去参加比赛了
You're not even in the game anymore.
-都是些垃圾  -我听到了  是垃圾
- It's all garbage. - I heard you. It's garbage.
别对我大声讲话
Don't get loud with me.
-这都怪你  -什么意思
- You're your problem. - What's that supposed to mean?
我为你做的够多了
I have been here for you a long time.
台前  幕后
In the ring, out of the ring,
看你折腾到这一步  我累了
and the whole ugly spiral down, and I'm tired.
我父亲倾其所有
My father invested everything
投入到你的搏斗事业  我们爱...
he had in your fight career. We loved...
他对你视如已出  这里就是他的家
He loved you like family. And this is his home.
我努力维持不让它垮掉  那就是我的计划
I'm just trying not to let it die. That's my plan.
你的计划是什么
What's yours?
你该放弃了吧
You're done, right?
你终于要放弃了吧
You're finally done?
因为我他妈的肯定不干了  查理
Because I sure as hell am, Charlie.
我一无所有了
I got nothing left.
好吧
All right.
也许这里有些东西
Maybe there's something here.
这个机器人是那孩子昨晚带回来的
This robot the kid brought in last night.
你愿意帮我看看它吗
Would you look at it for me?
拜托了
Please?
我以前从来没见过这种类型的机器人
I've never seen anything like it before.
它是第二代  但几乎绝产了
He's Generation Two, but barely.
我找到了适合它的电池
I found a power cell that fits him,
可以用旧型的第二代摇控器控制它
and I hooked him up to this old G-2 remote.
你可以让它动动  但它没什么用了
You can move him around, but he's crap.
也许我可以为它安排拳击比赛  赚几千块
Maybe I can get a sparring gig for him, make a few hundred bucks.
别妄想了
Stop.
它是我的机器人
It's my robot!
我花了半宿才把它从那里拖出来  它是我的
It took me half the night dragging him out of there. He's mine.
它是你的吗  好吧
He's yours? Yeah.
但装它身上的零件是我的
But the parts we're putting in him are mine!
你们两个笨蛋在争夺它之前
You idiots should least see if he powers up
至少先看看它能否通电启动吧
before you fight over him.
你怎么回事
What happened to you?
当心  后退
Watch out. Stay back.
看起来它还有模仿功能  非常罕见
Looks like he's got a shadow function. That's pretty rare.
它可以摸拟你们的动作  并记忆存储
He can mime your movements and store them in memory.
-还有什么我们可以用的东西吗  -不太多
- Is there anything here we could use? - Not much.
那里有个水桶
There's a bucket...
是我用来洗车的
There's a bucket I use to wash the truck.
用它给机器人洗洗  它太难闻了
Use it and clean him up. He smells like crap.
给它洗的时候你自己也洗洗  臭死了
Wash yourself off, too, while you're at it. You stink.
我将它调成遥控的了  非常简单
I switched him to remote. It's pretty basic.
只要用这个开关来控制它走路
Just use the toggles here to steer him and walk him.
-你玩电子游戏吧  -当然
- You play video games, right? - Of course.
同理  只不它是个有上千磅重的机器人
Same idea, only this one's a thousand-pound robot.
酷
Cool.
阿童木
"Atom."
它叫阿童木  我们可以让它参加比赛吗
His name is Atom. Can we get him a fight?
我觉得它以前不是一个拳击型机器人
I don't think he was ever a boxing robot.
它是第二代  建于2014年初期
He's a G-2, built in early 2014.
它过去是一个拳击训练机器人
He was a sparring bot.
他们建这样的机器人
They must have built robots like this one
一定是用来给其它战斗类型机器人陪练的
that could mirror the fighting style of any other robot.
好吧  那么我们可以让它参加比赛吗
OK, so can we get him a fight?
你没听我说吗  它是一个拳击训练机器人
Are you not listening? He's a sparring bot.
建它是为了挨打
Built to take a lot of hits,
但是永远不能承受真正的打斗
but never dishing out any real punishment.
你可以把它拆掉  按部件卖了
You could always sell him off for parts.
你就不能让它参加一次比赛吗
Can't you get him a fight?
"为什么你不能让它参加一次比赛"
"Why can't you get him a fight?"
天啊  你还没完没了了
God, you don't quit, do you?
你想让我把它
You want me to put him
放在职业拳击赛场去找死吗
in some bottom-rung scrap-fest to the death?
我看到你在撞击宫殿里害怕的样子了
I saw how scared you were at Crash Palace.
让你机器人比赛的地方
The places that would let you
会让你吓得屁滚尿流
fight this robot would make you pee your pants.
很好  带它去比赛吧
Excellent. Get him a fight.
顽固的小孩
Stubborn kid.
惊讶啊惊讶
Surprise, surprise.
我们去走走
Let's take a walk.
你能听懂我说话吗
Can you understand me?
别担心  我会替你保守秘密
Don't worry. Your secret's safe with me.
塔立的健身房  拳击馆
你认识查理很久了
You've known Charlie a long time.
太久了  我们在这个健身房里一起长大
Too long. We both kind of grew up in this gym.
我爸爸是他的教练
My dad, he trained him.
那是他们  那是查理
That's them. That's Charlie.
-他怎么样  -作为拳击手吗
- What was he like? - As a boxer?
-任何方面  -他是个人物
- As anything. - He was something.
他很瘦  很顽强
He was lean, tough.
永不放弃  无所畏惧
No quit, no fear.
过来  我想给你看点东西
Come here. I want to show you something.
我留了这份2007年的菲尼克斯报
I have this newspaper article from Phoenix 2007
查理和顶级挑战者尼科·坦迪比赛
when Charlie fought Nico Tandy, the top contender.
你参加了尼科·坦迪那场比赛吗
You were at the Nico Tandy fight?
是的  查理本来是要打垫场赛
I was. Charlie was supposed to be a warm-up fight,
让对方轻松取胜的
an easy win.
尼科本以为获胜轻而易举  但是
Nico wasn't even supposed to break a sweat, but...
没人告诉查理这是热身赛
...nobody told Charlie that,
结果他不停的攻向对手
so he just kept coming and coming at him.
看看这个
Check this out.
说的就是查理
That's Charlie.
伊始  尼科未料到无名小卒竟如此勇猛
First, Nico couldn't believe the balls on this nobody.
但在查理的猛攻下
But Charlie kept coming,
尼科流露出畏惧的神色
and that's when Nico looked scared.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Really.
他把尼科耍的团团转
He was toying with Nico.
这名世界第二的一流选手
The top contender, number two in the world,
查理对付他却游刃有余
and Charlie was dancing with him.
那晚查理的身型飘忽不定
Charlie was floating inches off the canvas that night.
他像鬼魂一样
He was like a ghost.
尼科甚至都无法看清他
Nico couldn't even see him.
我能
I could.
他帅呆了
He was beautiful.
然后呢  查理打败尼科·坦迪了吗
So what happened? Did Charlie beat Nico Tandy?
没有  第十二回合尼科·坦迪两次击倒了我
No, Nico Tandy put me on my ass in the 12th round. Twice.
第二次我起不来了  时间到了
Second time for good. Lights out.
你带着比分领先优势
You were ahead on the scorecards
进入第十二回合
going into the 12th round.
尼科·坦迪打到了我
Nico Tandy rung my bell
并且在随后的三年里
and went on to be the
以不败战绩成为了世界冠军
undefeated world champ for the next three years.
他把你打倒了吗
He knocked you out?
是的  就像打到其他家伙一样
Yeah. So did a lot of guys.
你也打到过很多人
You knocked a lot of guys out, too.
-24负19胜  -这算什么战绩啊
- 24 and 19. - It's not exactly a career.
但每次都进入到淘汰赛
But every fight a knockout.
是呀
Yeah.
无论输赢  身体不倒  比赛不止
Win or lose, fight's not over till someone's on the mat.
身体不倒  比赛不止
Till someone's on the mat.
你老爸这样教导我
Your old man taught me that.
你当然是他教出来的
Damn straight he taught you that.
你还和谁交过手
Who else did you fight?
去把你的东西整理好
Go get your stuff together.
不需要  你打过冠军争夺赛吗
I don't need to. Did you fight for the title?
你要去
Yeah, you do.
我们一小时后出发  去整理吧
We leave in an hour. Go.
给
Wow. Here.
你留着吧
Keep it.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
我喜欢这孩子
I like that kid.
他也喜欢你
He likes you.
-查理我昨天的话  -不  不用多说
- Charlie, what I said yesterday was... - No, nothing more to say.
我今晚打算出发去亚特兰大
I'm heading off to Atlanta tonight
看看能否找到合伙人
to see if I can get a partner
或者凑点钱弄个新机器人
or raise money to get a new bot.
这是你希望的  不是吗  让我走
That's what you wanted, right? Me gone?
对  我就是这样想的
Yeah, that's what I wanted.
好吧
Ok.
快看
Look.
冠军在这  宙斯就在这
The champ is here. Zeus is here.
是的
Yeah.
宙斯  与这怪兽交手
Zeus! No one has ever gone
没有人能挺过两回合  两回合
two rounds with this monster. Two rounds!
这位冠军今晚要为他的
The champ puts his Real Steel
铁甲钢拳桂冠之名而战
world championship belt on the line tonight.
他的双拳可不是做做样子的
He just may have a real fight on his hands.
宙斯  史上最伟大的机器人拳手
Zeus, greatest robot boxer of all time.
故事讲完了  晚安
Ever. End of story. Good night!
-太酷了 这太酷了  -什么
- So cool. It's so cool. - What?
听着  我要去找费恩
Listen up. I got to go find Finn.
我要你待在这儿
I want you to stay in this area.
请为冠军让下路  宙斯来了
Out of the way. Champ coming through. Zeus coming through.
让一下  让一下  让冠军过去
Move, move. Champ coming through.
法勒·拉莫科娃  宙斯团队父女组合之女
Farra Lemkova, daughter behind the father/daughter Zeus team.
人们说你父亲负责经济支持
They say your father's the money
而你是宙斯的灵魂
and you are the mind behind Zeus.
你太客气了
You're very kind,
但我向你保证
but I assure you,
宙斯的灵魂是伟大的达克·马西多
the mind behind Zeus belongs to the great Tak Mashido.
是什么让这位隐居的天才
What did it take to lure the reclusive genius, former boy wonder
曾经的青年才俊
and arguably the most important
该运动史上最有价值的机器人设计师
bot designer in the history of the sport
重现江湖呢
out of retirement?
你何不亲自问问他本人呢
Why don't you ask him yourself?
这是达克·马西多最伟大的作品吗
Is this Tak Mashido's greatest creation?
宙斯实现了自主控制
Zeus is autonomous
并且可以在战斗中不断的得到提升
and constantly evolving during a fight.
他通过自适应操作系统
With his adaptive operating system,
可以识别不同模式
he recognizes patterns
并即时更新战斗程序
and rewrites his fight code instantaneously.
我想代表自己和那边的乔·希克斯帕克问一下
For myself and Joe Sixpack out there,
你是说宙斯
are you saying that Zeus...?
我是说无论在赛场上发生什么
I'm saying that no matter what happens in that ring...
比赛的结果都是一样的
...the result of any fight is inevitable.
被宙斯盯上
What Zeus sees...
就死定了
...he kills.
太帅了
Sweet.
我绝对不会和你做生意
I'm never going into business with you.
我只需要一会儿时间
I just need a break here.
你有一辆老式机器人卡车停在外面
You got that old bot truck out there.
里面总有些存货
You always got something in there.
是一个老式拳击机器人  不值几个钱
I got an old sparring bot, ain't worth the paint left on it.
我能做什么
What am I supposed to do with that?
动物园  带它去动物园
The Zoo. Take him to the Zoo.
明天那有比赛
They fight there tomorrow.
即使是我也不会去动物园出洋相
Even I wouldn't be caught dead at the Zoo.
我只需要借点钱
I just need a little loan.
什么
What?
你说真的吗  查理
You're serious, Charlie?
借点钱而已
A loan.
两百  几百都行  随便你
Couple hundred. Few hundred. Whatever you got.
你知道我很在行
You know I'm good for it.
我了解你
I know you,
就像我喜欢你一样  哥们
and as much as I like you, dude...
你逢赌必输  哥们
...you're a bad bet, brother.
是呀
Right, yeah.
你看见了吗  那是阿克塞尔罗德的残骸
Did you see that? That's what's left of Axelrod.
你去哪了  我告诉过你在那等着
Where have you been? I told you to stay put.
你应该看看宙斯的表演  帅呆了
You should have seen him. Zeus was, like, amazing!
帅呆了 是吗
Amazing, huh?
是的  难以置信
Unbelievable, yeah.
他只是不停用拳头对付阿克塞尔罗德
He was just peppering Axelrod with punches,
但是速度快的难以置信
but so fast. It was incredible.
阿克塞尔罗德都没有机会反击
Axelrod didn't even land a punch.
他第一回合都没挺过去
He didn't even survive the first round.
你觉得这就是拳赛吗
Is that what you think boxing is?
宙斯狂扁送死的小喽喽
Zeus beating up some piece of steel that they feed him?
阿克塞尔罗德不是小喽喽
Axelrod's not just some piece of steel.
而且拳赛就是这样
And that is what boxing is now.
面对现实吧  我喜欢它
Deal with it. And I love it,
我已经参与其中了
and I'm in it now.
你融入其中了吗
You're in it now, are you?
和你的第二代拳击机器人吗
You and your G-2 sparring bot?
它实际上厉害多了
He's more than that.
如果你让我们比一次  你就知道了
If you'd get us a fight, you'd see.
你走运了  小子
You're in luck, kid.
有一个叫动物园的好地方
There's a lovely place called the Zoo.
明天下午  你就可以比赛了
Tomorrow afternoon, you'll get your fight.
-好极了  -而且仅此一场
- Great. - And it will be the end.
我跟你说过我讨厌汉堡
I told you I hate hamburgers!
这是墨西哥卷饼
It's a burrito!
右勾拳
Right uppercut.
左勾拳
Left uppercut.
下蹲  两手向上跳起来
Bend your knees. Rise up with both hands.
再来  下蹲  双手向上跳起来
Again. Bend your knees. Rise up with both hands.
你一晚没睡吗
You been up all night?
恩  我把它弄干净了
Yeah. I cleaned him up.
我正在用模拟模式来编辑
I'm using shadow mode to program
一些动作并把这些动作同步给遥控器
some fight moves and sync them to the remote.
好  我看到你教它跳拳了
Yeah. I saw that double-up punch you were showing him.
这招是必杀技
That's lethal stuff.
我们一起完成它
Let's do this.
我们还是先做早饭吧
Let's do breakfast first.
你准备好了把它的残骸运回家了 对吧
You know you're bringing him home in pieces, right?
等着瞧吧
We'll see.
-交给我吧  -查理·肯顿  这是麦克斯
- Let me deal with this. - Charlie Kenton. This is Max.
狒狒  叫我狒狒好了
Kingpin. Call me Kingpin.
-好的  狒狒  -一回合多少钱
- All right, Kingpin, so... - How much a round?
我们在做学生实习吗
We on a field trip?
好吧  它可以和我的机器人麦托打
All right. He can fight my robot Metro.
两分钟一回合我付你一百块
I'll give you a hundred bucks for one two-minute round.
-答应吧  -三百
- Take it. - Three hundred.
一百  小毛孩  我会付给你一百块
One hundred. Baby boy, I'm going to give you $100
仅仅是和麦托练练手
just to get in with Metro.
五百两回合怎么样
How about 500 for two rounds?
两回合  孩子  它一回合都顶不住
Two rounds. Son, he ain't going to survive one round.
-如果顶住了呢  -不可能
- What if he does? - He ain't.
我们假设它可以呢
Let's just say he does.
如果一回合结束它还能站着
If he's still standing after one round...
我给你一千块
...I'll give you a thousand bucks.
闭嘴
Shut it!
但如果它在这挂了
But if he dies in there,
它肯定会的  年轻人
which he will, junior...
它的残骸我也要
...I get to keep what's left.
接受一百块吧
Take the hundred.
成交
Deal.
我们开始  可以开始了
We're on. We on!
我们走
Let's go!
你应该接受一百块的交易
You should have taken the hundred.
我为咱们搞到一千块的
I got us a thousand.
前提是如果它能赢
Yeah, if he wins.
你需要我来控制吗
You want me to drive?
他是我的  我来
He's my bot. I got this!
这不是打电动
This ain't a video game.
这里是玩真的
This is for real. Right here.
你说它会死无全尸
You said he's coming home in pieces.
谁来控制又有啥区别呢
What difference does it make?
好吧
All right.
我能行
I got this.
让我们开始吧  我们开始吧
Let's get it on! Let's get it on!
让我们开始吧  就像在香港打乒乓球
Let's get it on like Ping-Pong in Hong Kong!
让开始铃声响起来吧
Give me a bell! Give me a bell!
别盯着阿童木  注意你的对手
Don't watch Atom. Watch your opponent.
小心它的脚  它想把你踩住
Watch out for that foot. He's looking to pin you.
我跟你说过要注意它的脚部动作
I told you to watch for that foot plant.
加油
Come on.
流星拳来了
Here comes the sledgehammer.
你们看见了吗
Did you see that?
加油  打倒它
Come on! Get him!
别干对他喊  要操纵它
Don't yell at him, control him.
向右滑步  后撤步
Slip right. Back step.
闪避
Duck.
-不用谢我  -闭嘴  你在帮倒忙
- You're welcome. - Shut up! You're not helping!
实际上  我在帮忙
Actually, I think I am.
后手拳  你得比这家伙快
Backhand. You got speed on this guy.
保持移动  跳动
Just keep moving. Bob.
离开角落  保持移动  迂回跳动
Slip out of that corner. Keep moving! Bob and weave!
就是这样  现在肯听我的了
That's it! Now you're listening to me.
它能承受打击  这我肯定
He can take a hit. I'll give you this.
你的机器人受得住猛打
Your bot can take a hit.
你最好摆脱这招锁头
You better slip that headlock.
这样下去你就完了
This ain't gonna end well for you.
我在努力
I'm trying!
还有三十秒
Thirty seconds!
三十...半分钟
Thirty... half a minute.
还有半分钟  保持移动  动起来
Half a minute! Keep moving! Just move!
还有二十秒
You've got 20 seconds!
那可是一千块
That's a thousand bucks.
还有二十秒  让我来操作它
Twenty seconds. Let me take over!
移动  继续移动
Move, then. Move!
加油
Come on.
站起来阿童木  站起来阿童木
Get up, Atom. Get up, Atom.
跟我一起数  跟我一起数  一
Count with me! Count with me! One!
站起来
Get up!
你知道你在对机器说话吗
You know you're talking to a machine?
四  五  六
Four! Five! Six!
站起来  阿童木
Get up, Atom!
保持住  保持住
All the way up! All the way up!
太棒了  太棒了
Yes! Yes!
我来处理
I'm going to fix it!
我会解决它  现在继续
I'm going to fix it! Come on, now.
-这是一千块  -是的  一千
- This thousand bucks... - Yeah, thousand.
翻倍或全输赌它不会挺过下一回合
Double or nothing he can't make another round.
不必了  多谢
Yeah, thanks anyway.
成交  翻倍或全输
Deal. Double or nothing.
这小子答应了  我们继续 继续
Baby boy said it! We're back on! We on!
你疯了吗  你就这样扔了一千块
Are you crazy? You threw away a thousand bucks!
它在那儿站都站不稳
He can barely stand up in there.
我真的需要这笔钱
Look. I really need the money.
我知道  我们开工吧
I know. Let's work.
天呐
Jesus.
-小心 小心  -我知道
- Watch that. Watch that. - I got that.
-我搞定  -这是系统崩溃
- I got it. - That's a system failure!
-我控制不了了  -它要完蛋了
- I don't got it. - He's going down.
-成了  -不
- Yes! - No!
开始读秒
Start the count!
一  二  三
One! Two! Three!
四  五  六  七
Four! Five! Six! Seven!
八  九
Eight! Nine!
十
Ten!
我们赢了  我们赢了
You did it! We did it! Wow!
该走了  带上你的机器人
Time to go. Come on. Grab your robot.
我知道  我知道  我知道
I know, I know! I know! I know!
狒狒  给钱
Kingpin, pay up.
好  好  好
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我知道  我知道  我知道
I know, I know, I know.
我们赢了
We owned!
我们走  快走  快走
Let's go. Come on, come on.
-什么事  -我有场比赛你要不要打
- Yeah? - Have I got a fight for you.
星期六晚上  押金四千
Saturday night. Guaranteed four grand.
赢了给七千
Seven if he wins.
四千吗  一言为定  我们走
Four grand? You're on. Let's go!
贝莉  是我  我们赢了
Bailey, it's me. He won.
你相信吗  这小子的机器人竟然赢了
Can you believe that? The kid's robot actually won.
我知道
I know.
高兴吗  我的天  是的
Happy? Oh, my God. Yeah.
他有点难搞  他真有点难对付
He's been bit. He's been bit real bad.
不管怎样
Anyway...
我只是想让你知道
I just wanted you to know.
刺拳  刺拳 勾拳
Jab, jab, hook.
刺拳  刺拳  勾拳
我觉得你应该动动脚
I think you have to move your feet.
你的脚  脚
Your feet. Feet.
跳的不错  孩子
Nice moves, kid.
你出来多久了
How long you been out here?
你听着
Check it out.
我花了一晚上做了件很酷的事
I just spent the night doing something I think is amazing.
非常了不起
Incredibly amazing.
如果能起作用话
If it works, you know?
你知道他的遥控器有点紊乱吧
You know his remote was spotty?
是的
Yeah.
我找到方法解决它了
I killed it. Got rid of it.
我们不再需要遥控器了
We don't need it anymore.
你怎么弄的
How did you?
我得重新调试
I had to start over.
我用伏击者的旋转结构
But I was able to use the spin frame from Ambush
和超恶男子的电路
and take the circuitry sleeve out of Noisy Boy,
然后它起作用了
and it works.
不知道怎么回事  但有用
He knows nothing, but it works.
它真的  真的管用了
It really, really works.
什么管用了
What works?
我得把它打开
I got to turn it on.
左刺拳  右勾拳
Left jab, right uppercut!
日本
Japan!
你把超恶男的声音识别模块给了阿童木
You put Noisy's voice recognition into Atom?
-太聪明了  小子  -就只是聪明吗
- Pretty smart, kid. - Smart?
简直是天才
It could be genius!
这可能是世界史上
It could be the most incredible
最不可思议的事
thing in the history of the entire world!
小心点  老大
Easy there, chief.
这些饮料都是你喝的吗
Did you drink all these sodas?
我也许喝了一些  我需要你教它拳击
I might have had a few. I need you to teach him to box.
你在跟我开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
他还没先进到掌握超恶男的声控指令
He's not advanced enough to handle Noisy's voice command.
所以它需要学习你的动作  你的指令
So he needs your moves. Your commands.
-从零开始  -得了吧
- Start over from the ground up. - Forget it.
你是一名拳击手
You were a boxer.
昨天在动物园
Yesterday at the Zoo,
你甚至可以预见对手的动作
you could see things happen before they even happened.
我有好长时间没练拳击了
I haven't boxed in a long time.
我不想现在开始练
I'm not starting now.
-谁来教它打比赛  -你做的就不错
- Who's going to teach him to fight? - You're doing fine.
你不需要我  抱歉
You don't need me. Sorry.
不过  刚才的舞蹈真的很酷
That was really cool, though, that dance.
你该在周六晚上表演一下
You should do that on Saturday night.
-别取笑我  -我是认真的
- Don't make fun of me. - I'm serious.
在比赛前  在你们入场时
Before the fight, when you guys take the ring,
你应该表演一下
you should do it.
我和一个机器人在一群拳击观众面前跳舞
There's no way I'm dancing
这不太可能
with a robot in front of a boxing crowd.
你跟我开玩笑吗  这只是表演
Are you kidding me? This is just a show.
人们乐于看些新鲜玩意儿
People want to see something they've never seen.
你想想那些名人
Look. You think of all the greats.
想想阿里  糖果·瑞恩  王子拉基姆  老妪
Think Ali, Sugar Ray, Prince Rakim, Gammer,
他们都有绰号
they all had their nicknames.
他们都很有个性  他们都有才华
They had their personas. They all had flair.
而你呢  你可能没有几个机器人
Now you? You might not have much robot,
但是你可以通过舞蹈展现才华
but with that dance, you got flair.
再说  你还是孩子
Plus, you're a kid.
人们喜欢孩子
People love that kid thing.
你多大了  九岁还是十岁啊
What are you? Like nine? Ten?
我十一岁了
I'm 11.
你肯定十一岁了吗
Are you sure you're 11?
是的  我确实十一岁了
Yes. I'm sure I'm 11.
不管怎样  关键是人们喜欢看
Anyway, the point is people want to see that.
你真的不是在逗我吗
You're really not messing with me?
我是认真的  他们会喜欢的
I am not messing with you. They're going to love it.
-好的  -但是
- Cool. - But...
-什么  -除非你帮我要不我不跳
- What? - I won't do it unless you help me.
我不会跳  你的自己上
I can't dance. You're on your own there.
不  我是说拳击
No. Boxing.
-我知道了  -我为机器人编程
- Oh, I see. - I program the robot.
-你教它拳击  -你就跳舞
- You teach him to box. - And you dance.
你跳舞
And you dance.
-好吧  -答应了
- Yeah. - Yeah?
成交
Deal.
到时会很酷的
It's going to be cool.
很棒
Nice.
你会和大个子交手
You're going to be punching guys bigger.
你出拳要高一些
You're going to have to punch up.
就像这样
That's it.
很好
Nice.
你也扭到了吗  老家伙
You, too, old man?
来吧  我们开始练吧
Come on. Let's get to work.
很好  我们再来
Nice! Let's do that again.
很好  三拳组合
Nice. Three-punch combo.
组合拳
Combo.
再来  再来
Again. Again.
快一点  快一点  很好
Faster. Faster. Nice.
你都不会累  我喜欢
You're not even out of breath. I like it.
我们看看你的移动如何
Let's see how you move.
很不错
That's good.
脚步动起来  左勾拳  左勾拳
Step around! Left hook! Left hook!
就这样  保持住
That's it. Every time.
上勾拳
Upper cut!
打得漂亮  哥们
Great fight, fellas.
这里是调频105.5  WRUT频道
105.5, WRUT,
机器人拳击的空中之家
the satellite home of robot boxing.
二号来电听众  你要爆什么料
Caller two, what do you got for me?
你听没听说过一个小个子机器人
Have you heard about this little bot out there,
叫阿童木的
his name is Atom?
必须听过
Oh, yeah.
我和几个哥们有天晚上看见他了
My buddies and I saw him the other night,
他跳舞来着
and he dances.
-你是说跳舞吗  -没错
- Did you say "Dances"? - You heard me.
他和那个小孩赛前跳舞热身
He dances pre-fight with this little kid,
观众爱死他们了
and the crowd went nuts for these two.
先把这噱头放一放
You put the gimmick aside for a second,
我手里有张单子  写着被他击败的对手
and I'm holding here a list of the bots he's beaten.
混乱  华尔街  独眼杰克
Chaos. Wall Street. One-Eyed Jack.
这上头没一个孬种  是吧
No slouches on that list, right?
连本带利
查理
阿童木跟他们全打过  把他们全打败了
Atom's fought them all, beat them all.
我跟你说  这个机器人步伐极快
I'm telling you, Tommy, this bot is fast!
他会躲开那些大个子的拳头  太厉害了
He escapes shots from these bigger bots, it's insane!
毫无疑问  听我说  听众朋友们
No doubt. I'm telling you, listeners,
记住这个名字
you remember this name
阿童木  没错  A-T-O-M
Atom. That's right, A-T-O-M.
这个机器人前途无量
This bot is one to watch.
-干的漂亮  -多谢  多谢
- Awesome fight, sir. - Thanks, thanks.
打得漂亮
Great fight.
-你们让比赛值回票价  -谢谢
- You guys put on a good show. - Thanks.
我们想邀请你们去打场比赛
We'd like to invite you to fight on our card,
维珍全美系列赛  底特律赛区  周五晚
Virgin America Spectrum Detroit, Friday night.
好的  那是世界机器人拳击锦标赛
Right. That's a WRB...
是冠军联赛
That's a League fight.
如假包换  怎么样  伙计们
Damn right it is. What do you say, fellas?
准备参赛吗
You ready for the show?
就等这一天呢
Heck, yeah.
这是正式赛前的比赛  但也属于联赛
It's the undercard, but it's still a League fight.
我希望你放松  你要放轻松
I just want you to be relaxed. I want you to be relaxed.
别崩溃了  别给我吓得屁滚尿流的
No freaking out. Don't get all freaky-deaky on me.
你要是吓傻了  这事就完蛋了
You go freaky-deaky, this whole thing can go south.
干什么事都得乐在其中  自娱自乐
Whatever you do, have fun, have fun.
自娱自乐  明白吗
You got to have fun, you understand me?
我们要是在赛场上崩溃了
We've come too far to get out there
搞砸了  我们就白来了
and freak out and blow this whole thing.
我们要乐在其中  绝不崩溃
We're going to have fun, and we're going to not freak out!
我们要放轻松  骗过他
We're going to stay loose, and we're just going to bam him.
我一辈子都想打进这个比赛  我们要
I've spent my whole life waiting to get here. We're going to...
我跟你说  相信我不能崩溃  明白吗
I tell you what. Trust me when I say no freaking out. You got it?
-我明白  -很好
- I got it. - Good.
你们被邀请进入拉莫科娃套间  请跟我来
You have been invited to Lemkova Suite. Follow me, please.
什么玩意  再说一遍
What was that? One more time.
拉莫科娃套间  宙斯套间
Lemkova Suite. Zeus Suite.
当然  好的  去冠军套间  走
Sure. Yeah. Let's head up to the champ's suite. Sure.
先生们  我是法勒·拉莫科娃
Gentlemen, I'm Farra Lemkova.
在下查理·肯顿
Yeah. I'm Charlie Kenton, and...
这位  当然了  就是达克·马西多
And this, of course, is Tak Mashido.
我的天哪  那是达克·马西多
Holy shit. It's Tak Mashido.
我了解你们今晚有一场非常重要的比赛
I know you have a very important fight tonight,
所以我就直说了
so I'll get right to it.
这招和我惯用的不太一样
It's a little far from the action for my liking.
但是不赖  我喜欢
It's nice. I like it, though.
干净利落  这照片拍得不错
Very nicely... Wow. That's a great shot.
看看  你想合个影吗  您介意
Look at that. You want an autograph? Would you mind?
我想买你们的机器人
I'd like to buy your robot.
他会很适合给宙斯当陪练
He'd be useful sparring bot for Zeus.
因此我愿意出大价钱
And for that I'm willing to pay.
二十万
$200,000.
-成交  -他是非卖品
- Done. - He's not for sale.
-当然卖  我们绝对  -他是非卖品
- Of course he is. We can definitely... - He's not for sale.
你们跟双头怪的
You are 15 minutes away
比赛还有十五分钟开始
from getting in the ring with Twin Cities,
他可是个邪恶的联赛机器人
a vicious League bot.
所以  听清楚
So, to be clear,
我的出价在比赛开打之前都是有效的
my offer stands until the starting bell.
好的  你也听清楚  他是非卖品
OK. And just to be clear, he's not for sale!
现在是  永远是
Not now, not ever.
给我一分钟来搞定  好吗
Give me a minute to clear this up, OK?
麦克斯  麦克斯  麦克斯
Max! Max! Max!
放聪明点吧  我知道你爱他
Be smart. I know you love him,
但二十分钟后他就剩不下什么让你爱了
but in 20 minutes there may be nothing left to love.
-想想清楚  成交了吧  -你想清楚
- Think about it. Take the offer. - You think about it.
她为什么想买阿童木
Why does she want Atom?
因为他跟其他的机器人不一样
Because he's different from other bots!
是  他是不一样  他更小  更弱
Yeah, he's different. He's smaller, weaker,
-而且他会输得很惨  -他是个拳击手
- and he's going to get his ass kicked. - He's a boxer.
我们教会他打拳击  你教会他打拳击
We taught him to box. You taught him to box!
-那是有价值的  -我也觉得他有价值
- That's worth something. - I think it is, too.
我觉得他值二十万  整整二十万啊
I think it's worth 200 grand. Two hundred grand.
我能跟你耗一晚上
We can go round and round this all night long.
看着我
Look at me.
但是我不会卖掉他
But it's not going to happen.
我还得去参加比赛呢
I got a fight to get to.
女士们先生们  今夜
Ladies and gentlemen, tonight,
铁甲钢拳冠军赛的胜出者
the march towards the Real Steel Championship
将晋级底特律赛区的
makes its way through Detroit's
维珍全美系列赛
Virgin America Spectrum!
今晚的开场比赛  第一场垫场赛的选手
Kicking off the evening, in our first undercard,
是双头暴君
the two-headed tyrant,
双头怪
Twin Cities!
他的对手是第一次参加职业比赛的
Opposing Twin Cities, in his first professional fight,
黑马
hailing from parts unknown,
阿童木
Atom!
-跳得好  老大  -谢了
- Nice work, boss. - Thanks.
-你把他调成战斗模式了吗  -当然
- Did you switch him to fight mode? - Of course.
这家伙可不好对付
This bot is tough to put down.
阿童木应付得来
Atom can do it.
往那看
Look over there.
看见那两个摆弄操纵杆和仪表板的极客了吗
You see those geeks with the joysticks and consoles?
他们控制那个机器人的所有活动
They're controlling everything their bot does.
他们监控他的系统
They're monitoring his systems,
见他所见的体育场环境  比赛走向等等
seeing what he sees, stadium, feeds of the fights, everything.
这跟我们以前参加的地下
This is not like the underground
手动遥控机器人比赛不一样
handheld remote bots we've been fighting.
这是联赛  记住这点
This is the League. Stand on that.
那我们怎么办
So what do we do?
打得聪明点  有耐心  然后祈祷
We fight smart, we be patient. And pray.
说真的  祈祷吧
Seriously, pray.
准备好了吗
Ready!
-准备好了吗  -手举起来
- Ready! - Hands up.
选手准备就绪  开始
Fighters ready! Fight!
上吧
Engage.
闪开  右手拳  后倾  右  左
Slip! Right! Lean back. Right, left!
掩护自己
Cover up!
闪避  左臂挥拳
Duck! Left roundhouse!
妈的
Damn it.
左倾  右倾  掩护  掩护
Lean left! Lean right! Cover up! Cover up!
-怎么回事  -他挨了太多下了
- What's going on in there? - He's taking too many hits.
把手举起来
Get your hands up!
从那死角里出去  动起来
Get out of that corner! Move!
查理  快点
Come on, Charlie.
他会死在这的  告诉他该怎么做
He's getting killed in there! Tell him what to do!
这家伙有俩脑袋
That guy's got two heads,
打赢我们一步之遥  而且没有盲点
a foot of reach on us, and no blind spot.
他肯定有弱点  找到它
He's got to have a weakness. Find it!
等等  等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait.
右肩  右肩  弱点在右肩
Right shoulder, right shoulder, right shoulder! He's got a tell!
每次他挥右拳
He's got a hitch in his
他的肩都猛拉一下
shoulder every time he throws that right bomb!
我们搞定他  看见了吗  又来了
We got him! See? Here it comes again!
闪避  转回来  滑向右侧  挥拳
Duck! Spin! Slide left! Roundhouse!
一  二
One, two!
后退  后退  后退  右倾
Backstep. Backstep. Backstep. Lean right.
上啊  查理  干掉他
Come on, Charlie! Get in there!
我们得贴近他让他打不着
Got to get in close where he can't use that size and reach on us!
打他身体左侧  身体右侧  身体左侧
Left to the body! Right to the body! Left to the body!
这招有用
Yeah, it's working!
蹲低位  左右左出拳
Stay downstairs! Left, right, left!
这些程序模式罢工了
These program modes aren't working.
左拳  右勾拳  溜开
Left! Right hook, slip!
右上钩拳  左上钩拳
Right uppercut! Left uppercut!
向左闪避  右拳还击
Duck left. Counter right!
-干掉他  阿童木  -看我的绝招
- Get him, Atom! - Here comes the Charlie Special.
三拳组合打他躯干  退  进  还击
Three-punch combo to the body! Out! In! Counter!
-二一二  -二一二
- Two-one-two! - Two-one-two.
跟紧他  击打右侧
Stay on him! Lunging right!
别放过他  击打躯干  直接打头
Don't let him go. Right to the body! Straight right to the head!
系统崩溃了
We got a systems crash!
干掉他  阿童木
Get him, Atom!
别这样  天哪
This is not happening, man.
-放倒他  查理  -左转
- Put him away, Charlie! - Spin left!
右转
Spin right!
干掉他
Finish him!
-上啊  -右上钩拳
- Do it! - Right uppercut!
他倒下了
He's down!
一  二  三
One! Two! Three!
四  五  六
Four! Five! Six!
我们干掉他了  别起来
We got him. Stay down!
他输了  他输了
He's out! He's out!
太棒了
Yeah!
到这个角里
Corner!
过来  过来
Corner! Corner.
胜利了
Victory!
在不到一分钟的时间里  在第一轮的
In a time of one minute, 47 seconds
第四十七秒
of the first round,
阿童木击败了
Atom has defeat...
感谢大家今晚的到来
I want to thank everyone for coming out tonight!
我们来自废品场的小家伙将有机会进联赛
Our little bot from the junkyard got a shot at a League fight.
怎么样
How about that?
最后我想对不愿直呼其名的女孩说
And the last thing I want to say to a special girl who won't be named,
法勒·拉莫科娃
Farra Lemkova.
别再企图买我的机器人
That instead of buying my robot,
用你的钱控制比赛
using your money to control this sport...
-够了  -我还没说完
- That's it! - I'm not done.
为什么不给小个子一个更大的机会
Why not give the littlest guy the biggest shot?
我打赌你要是给他一个机会
Because I bet if you give him a shot,
他就会给你个惊喜
he'll surprise you!
你们不想看看一个小个子
Wouldn't you like to see a little guy
出现在铁甲钢拳冠军赛里吗
get a shot at the Real Steel Championship?
我在此向宙斯宣战
I challenge Zeus to a fight.
时间地点任您挑选
Any time, any place, anywhere!
你敢应战  我们随时奉陪
You name it! We will be there!
我们要去跟他打一场
I'm going to get us that fight!
阿童木  阿童木  阿童木
Atom, Atom, Atom...
你吃豹子胆了  怎么敢那么挑战宙斯
That was a ballsy move, you challenging Zeus like that.
话也不能那么说
That's one thing to call it.
有的是人想看这场比赛
A lot of people would like to see that.
你说的太对了
You're damn right they would.
听听这孩子的口气  天哪
You listening to this kid? Jeez!
-干得漂亮  伙计们  -谢谢
- Good fight, fellas. - Thanks, man.
-看这些钱  咱们庆祝庆祝  -好啊
- Look at this. Let's celebrate. - Yeah.
三七分怎么样
All right, 70-30, right?
行啊  我七你三
Yeah, 70 for me and 30 for you.
-多好啊  -别逗了
- That's so right. - That's very funny.
-我就说不应该把他卖了  -得了吧
- I told you we shouldn't have sold him. - OK. No, no, no.
我还记得呢  谁说的对
I remember now. Who's right?
说谁说的对  说我说得对
Say who's right. Say "Max is right."
行  行  行
All right, all right. All right.
-团队合作嘛  -不行  我才是对的
- We're a good team. - No, no. Max is right.
太难以置信了  谢谢你  双头怪
That was unbelievable. Thank you, Twin Cities.
-收拾好了吗  -好了
- We set? - Yeah.
-我们走吧  -查理老弟
- Let's do it. - Charlie boy.
里奇  我还想给你打电话来着
Ricky, I was just going to call you.
是吗
Oh, yeah.
我真打算给你打电话
I actually really was going to call you.
别操心打电话这事了
Don't worry about that.
刚刚这一战打得不赖啊
That was a heck of a fight.
恭喜你俩  很好啊
Congratulations to both of you. That was good.
打得太漂亮了  干得好  小伙子
It was an amazing fight. That was a great job, young man.
-别这样  -怎么样
- Come on, man. - What?
-你要来真的吗  -你以为我逗你玩呢
- You serious? - You thought I was joking
你以为我说我要把你打个半死是逗你玩呢
when I said I'd beat you within an inch of your life?
他以为我开玩笑呢  那可不是玩笑
He thought that was a joke. It wasn't a joke.
我这还有个孩子呢  我把钱还你
I got a kid here. And I have your money.
问题解决了
We don't have a problem.
我看没解决
I'm sure you do,
你我都知道这不光是钱的问题  对吧
but I think we know it's about much more than money, don't we?
行了  你想要多少
All right. What do you want?
两万五  三万  三万够吗
You want 25, 30? You want 30 grand?
-我这有现金  -好啊
- I got the money in cash here. - Yeah, right.
快跑  麦克斯  快跑  快跑
Let's go! Max, go! Go, go! Run!
-跑  快点  跟上  -抓住他
- Run! Come on. Keep up, keep up! - Get him now!
跑  快跑
Run! Come on!
放开他  放开他
Get off him! Get off him!
过来
Come here!
看  里奇
Hey, Ricky.
那是他的钱  这事跟他无关
That's his money! Leave him out of this!
住手
Stop!
把他的钱全拿走  全拿走
Take all his money. Take it all.
你朋友是个卑鄙小人  孩子
Your friend's a real dirtbag, kid.
他是我爸爸
He's my father!
看来你都剩不下半条命了
Well. Looks like a little less than an inch of your life.
伙计  这一脚帮他长长记性
Well, buddy, that will teach him.
重回旧时光  查理老弟
Just like old times, Charlie boy!
我们走  伙计们
Let's go, boys.
对不起  麦克斯  对不起
I'm sorry, Max. I'm sorry. Sorry.
-我们来这干什么  -麦克斯  是
- What are we doing here? - Max, just...
是不是法勒  是不是她给你打电话了
Is it Farra? She called you, didn't she?
我们要和宙斯打一场了
We're going to get the Zeus fight.
不是宙斯那帮人
It's not the Zeus people.
我想了很多  然后
I've been thinking about all this, and...
麦克斯
Max!
看见你真高兴
It's so good to see you.
-她来干什么  -你最好跟她走
- What is she doing here? - It's better if you go with her now.
我们被打了  你就叫她过来把我接走吗
We get beat up, so you call her to come and get me?
他被打了  我告诉过你他照顾不好孩子
He's been beat up. I told you he couldn't take care of him!
对  我叫她来的 看看我们  一团糟
Yeah. I called her. Look at us. We're a mess.
我们很好  她可以走了
We're fine. She can leave!
阿童木打得很好  我们能把钱赚回来
Atom's fighting good. We can make the money back.
查理  求你了
Charlie, please.
但是
Just...
查理  我们过得很好
Charlie, we're doing so good.
查理  求你了  别这样
Charlie, please, no.
别  别  别
Don't. Don't. Don't.
求你了  求你
Please. Please.
相信我  孩子  你跟她走更好
Trust me, kid. It's better this way, all right?
我知道你以为你明白  可是你不懂
I know you think you know what's right, but you don't.
你还太小  你还不懂
You're too young. You don't know.
看着我  相信我
Look at me, trust me.
而且法律上监护权是她的  我能怎么办
And legally she has custody, so what can I do?
我能怎么办
What can I do?
我不想要你的钱  马文
I don't want your money, Marvin.
麦克斯  我们有私人游泳池
Max, we have our own swimming pool
有热水浴缸  还有好多超级好玩的玩具
and we have a hot tub and a lot of super fun toys to play with.
你不想玩吗  会很好玩的
Do you want to play with them? It's going to be fun.
怎么了
What's going on?
托你的福  查理  他不肯跟我说话了
He won't even talk to me, so thanks for that, Charlie.
我去车里等着
I'm going to wait in the car.
你不想讲话  那好  我来讲
You don't want to talk, fine. I'll talk.
你想让我说什么  我很抱歉吗
What do you want me to say? I'm sorry?
从第一天起你就很清楚
You knew from day one what this was.
你决定跟我待一阵子
You decided to take the ride.
你还指望你  我  还有个从垃圾场里
You thought me, you, and a little robot from the junk heap
挖出来的机器人能过一辈子吗  得了吧
were going to ride off into the sunset? Come on.
你忘了我过去是怎样一个人
No, you forgot who I was!
你值得和比我更好的人
You deserve better...
一起生活
...than me.
说点什么  好吗
Will you say something, please?
我试过了  你还想要我怎么样
I tried. What do you want from me?
我希望你能为我争取一下
I want you to fight for me.
我想要的就这么多
That's all I ever wanted.
别问
Don't ask.
麦克斯走了
So no Max.
这样比较好  老马和黛布拉有钱
It's better this way. Marv and Debra have money.
麦克斯能生活的很好
Max is set.
你没注意到他看着你的样子吗
Did you not see the way he looked at you?
我就是那样看我父亲的
That's the way I looked at my dad.
即使现在我也宁愿牺牲一切把他换回来
Even now I would give anything to have that back.
你的父亲很特别
Your dad was special.
从第一天起他就出现在你的生活里
He was in your corner from day one.
我不行  我搞砸了
Me, come on. I blew it.
我搞砸了
I blew it.
麦克斯出生的时候我
When Max was born I just...
我吓坏了
...freaked out.
但是有个爸爸总比没有好
But something would have been better than nothing.
我不知道该怎样开始
I wouldn't know where to start.
-你知道  -不
- Yeah, you do. - I don't.
- You do. - No.
你知道
You do.
我得走了
I got to go.
你跑了一千二百英里就为了索一个吻
Twelve hundred miles for a kiss.
值得  值得
Worth it. Worth it.
去找他  查理
Go get him, Charlie.
你说话跟你父亲一模一样
You sound like your dad.
听着  我知道你认为我抛弃了你
Look, I know you think I abandoned you,
我当初的确是抛弃你了
and I guess I did originally.
然后你又把我卖了
Then you sold me.
查理
Charlie.
你不应该来这里
You have no business being here.
的确  你有全部监护权  他属于你
That's true. You've got full custody. He's yours.
我知道我对不起这孩子
And I know I've done all kinds
但是请听我说
of wrong by this kid, but if you'll let me...
我只想做一件正确的事
...I'd just like to do one thing right.
好吧
Right.
-说到哪了  -你把我卖了
- Where were we? - You sold me.
对  没错
Right, yeah, that happened.
-等等  什么  -然后我们被打了
- Wait, what? - Then we had our asses kicked.
然后你睡在了卡车的架子上  很不舒服
And you slept on a shelf in a truck, and it was awful.
-而且危险  -非常危险
- And dangerous. - Really dangerous.
我知道  天哪  对不起
I mean, I know. God. I'm sorry.
这就是你来的目的吗  为了道歉
That's why you came? To say you're sorry?
不是  也对  是  是
No. I mean, yes. Yes.
但不全是  我来是告诉你我懂了
But no. No, I came to tell you that I heard you.
我懂了  反应有点慢  但是我懂了
I got it. I'm a little slow, but I got it.
我知道你跟我过得不好
I know you had a bum ride,
你需要我的时候我也不在你身边
and I wasn't there and I should have been.
我应该在的
I should have been.
你的妈妈
Your mom was...
她很棒  是吗
She was cool, wasn't she?
是的
She was.
她是最棒的
She was the coolest.
对  她是
Yeah, she was.
发生在她身上的事  我很难过
And I'm sorry about... what happened with her.
过去的日子我不能弥补  麦克斯
And I can't get those years back, Max,
但是我此时此刻
but I'm here right now...
如果你准备好了  我也准备好开战
...and if you're up for it, I'm ready to fight.
我们可以跟宙斯一较高下了
We got the Zeus fight.
什么
What?
不不  不是我们
No, no, we didn't.
是你可以和宙斯一较高下了
You got the Zeus fight.
就看你了  黛布拉
So what do you say, Debra?
你同意我们这最后一搏吗
Can we do this one last thing?
-就一晚上  -足够了  谢谢
- One night. - It's all we need. Thank you.
虽然搞不好我们会输很惨
We'll probably get our asses kicked,
但我们虽败犹荣
but at least we'll go down swinging.
怎么样  兴奋吗
Yeah? What do you say?
欢迎来到纽约必应体育场
Welcome to New York's Bing
观看机器人拳击大赛
Arena and the Real Steel Championship Bout.
蒂姆  今天的比赛与众不同啊
Tim, it's the fight we never thought we'd see.
宙斯  这位不可战胜的世界机器人
Zeus, the undefeated
拳击大赛冠军
WRB champion,
将要对决不起眼儿的冉冉新星阿童木
against the underdog, rising star Atom.
大赛组织者们都同意
The champ's handlers have agreed to fight
这场比赛独立于联赛之外
outside the circle of well-known League bots,
并决定带给大家献上一场
and have decided to give the
蚂蚁与大象决斗的精彩比赛
people a true David versus Goliath spectacle.
蒂姆  我没搞明白
Now, Tim, help me out on this.
宙斯团队脑袋进水了吧
Has the Zeus camp lost their mind?
史上最伟大的拳击机器人
The greatest robot boxer of all time
要和过时的二代机器人阿童木一较高下吗
gives a shot at the belt to a G-2 named Atom?
赫伯  如果你去问达克·马西多
Well, Herb, if you ask Tak Mashido,
宙斯团队确实有点不正常
Team Zeus has lost their minds.
他在进场时虽然很从容
Now, he may look cool as he enters the arena,
但是他满脸都是对对手的不屑一顾
but he has made no bones about his disdain for this matchup.
几天前我们的镜头捕捉到了这个画面
Our cameras tried to catch up with him earlier this week.
请看
Look at this clip.
马西多不愿对媒体多费一句口舌
Mashido wouldn't even stop to talk to the press,
这场比赛是对他所造机器人的羞辱
referring only to this fight as an insult to his creation.
这位麦克斯·肯顿  阿童木的教练
Now, Max Kenton, Atom's trainer,
付出了大量心血
did more than just challenge Zeus.
他在公开场合宣战
He did so publicly.
让比赛变得路人皆知
The challenge went viral
也让准冠军陷入公关危机
and created a PR nightmare for the champ.
毫无疑问
No argument there.
我认为宙斯团队也心知肚明
And I think the Zeus camp knows exactly what they're doing.
没错  来吧
That they do. Come on.
在这个不起眼儿的小子身上赌一把吧
Giving a shot at the belt to a nobody from nowhere.
我们就叫他"垃圾犬"  就算炒作好了
This "Junkyard dog," if you will. That's a marketing stunt.
从观众的反应来看  还真起作用了
And judging from this crowd, that stunt is working.
我们能赢吗
We can't win, can we?
走着瞧吧
We'll see.
当挑战者走进赛场
As the challenger makes his way into the arena,
观众们给予了热情的欢呼
you can hear the surge of excitement.
阿童木运用了所谓的拟人置式
Atom has arrived onto the WRB scene with a vengeance,
雄赳赳地来参加世界机器人大赛
using a style, some would call it human-like,
那种模式已经很少见了
that bot fighting has rarely seen.
两位身形相差悬殊的搭档步入了场地
Atom and his pint-size trainer step into the ring
法勒·拉莫科娃的表情说明了一切
and the look on Farra Lemkova's face says it all.
欢迎光临  菜鸟
Welcome to the bigs, junior!
我提供1赔5的赔率
I'm giving one-to-five odds
押阿童木过不了第一回合
that Atom don't make it out the first round.
谁想押注
Who wants some?
我来押
I'll take some of that action.
喂  我要押点
Hey, there! I'll take some of that action.
你好啊  同行
How's it going... partner?
同行
Partner?
好极了  我押10万如何  好笑吗
That's great. How about a hundred K? Is that funny?
10万押阿童木进不了第二回合
Hundred K says Atom doesn't see round two.
你随身带那么多钱了吗
You carrying around that kind of scratch?
-对  -有10万吗
- Yeah. - Hundred K?
告诉你  我在一区C排的一号座位
Tell you what. Remember section 101, row C,
你到时候直接把钱给我送来
and you can bring me my money right to my seat.
一区C排的一号座位  10万  对吗
101, row C? Hundred K?
你听见我说的了  老乡
You heard me, homey.
-老乡吗  -不是吗
- Homey? - Right?
乡仔
Homeboy!
好了  和气生财  伙计们
All right. Peace out, posse.
来吧  甜心  我们走
Come on, sugar. Let's go.
-天下无敌  -好戏开场了
- Never beaten. - It's showtime!
永不妥协
Never threatened.
拳击之王
The king of the ring,
机器人之王
the ruler of robots!
向万能的宙斯致敬
Bow down to the mighty Zeus!
我靠
Oh, shit!
了不起
That was awesome.
快  我们行动
Come on, let's go.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
在这场世界机器人拳击锦标赛上
in a bout scheduled for five rounds
将举行五个回合的较量
for the World Robot Boxing Championship,
在我右角的是挑战者  阿童木
in the corner to my right, the challenger, Atom!
耍几招
Showboat!
在我的左角
And in the corner to my left,
是这个星球乃至整个知与未知宇宙上
the undeniable champion of this universe
无可争议的总冠军
and any other universe known or unknown,
万能的宙斯
the mighty Zeus!
女士们先生们  机器人拳击大赛
And now, ladies and gentlemen, are you ready
现在开始
for Real Steel!
铁甲钢拳
这才像话嘛
This is what it's all about!
随着铃声响起  比赛正式开始
There's the starting bell and we are underway.
双方各就各位了
The bots emerge from their corners.
宙斯一击命中  阿童木倒了下去
Zeus decks Atom, and he is already down.
站起来
On your feet!
看起来又像是一场宙斯的教学比赛
Looks like we are in for another Zeus clinic.
裁判马特·甘格进入场地开始读秒
Referee Matt Geiger coming in the ring to start the count.
起来
Get up!
撑起来  站起来
Push up! Stand up!
看  小个子重新站了起来
But look at this. The little bot's back on his feet
而宙斯的重拳又一次击中了他
to get a second blistering attack from Zeus!
这是阿童木在十秒内第二次被击倒
Atom is down for the second time in less than ten seconds.
-他太厉害了  -那才像话嘛
- He's too strong! - That's my boy right there!
起来比赛
Get up and get in the game!
加油啊  求你了  阿童木  站起来
Come on! No, please Atom, get up! Please!
起来  起来  起来
Get up! Get up! Get up!
挑战者再次站了起来
Once again, the challenger finds his feet!
边避边退
Lean back!
阿童木逐渐被逼到了台角
Atom's getting pummeled into the corner!
-离开台角  -快
- Get out of there! - Move!
好一记摧枯拉朽的内勾拳
A demolishing inside shot.
双手挡住面门
Get your hands up!
挡住
Hands up!
把他锤成肉饼
Crush that little can!
离开台角
Get out of the corner!
肯顿玩命儿地叫着
Kenton desperately trying to
让他的拳手远离致命的角落
command his robot out of that suicide corner.
双脚站稳了
Get your feet under you!
晚安  陪练小子
Good night, sparring bot!
本来似乎要耗宙斯一点时间的
It might have taken Zeus a bit longer,
但他再次成功击倒对手
but he's done it again!
阿童木第三次倒下也可能是今晚的最后一次
Atom is down for the third and possibly final time tonight.
-站起来  -二
- Stand up! - Two!
三
Three!
阿童木  起来
Atom, get up!
-起来  阿童木  -起来  阿童木
- Get up, Atom. - Get up, Atom.
-六  七  -起来
- Six! Seven! - Get up!
八  九
Eight! Nine!
难以置信  他打破了所有的赔率
I don't believe this! Against all odds,
小个子再次站起来了
this little bot is on his feet again.
加油  阿童木
Come on, Atom!
不能这样挨下去
He can't survive this!
-加把劲  查理  -右勾拳
- Come on, Charlie! - Right uppercut!
阿童木反击了一拳
Atom has landed a punch!
宙斯被这突如其来的一记
Zeus is stunned as he reels
右勾拳打懵了
back from an uppercut that he never saw coming!
继续
Advance!
收拳  右拳反击
Fade back, counter right!
右直拳  右直拳  右直拳  左勾拳
Right cross! Right cross! Right cross! Left hook!
-加油  加油  -把他揍趴下
- Let's go! Come on! - Take him down!
这是他首次在优势的情况下遭遇反击
For the first time in his dominant run,
宙斯遇上了一个难缠的对手
Zeus has met a bot who simply won't back down!
现场观众如痴如狂  宙斯使出了看家本领
The crowd is going nuts! Zeus gives it everything he's got
力争在首回合结束前完成比赛
as we reach the last 15 seconds of round one!
宙斯把阿童木逼到了台角  使出双臂组合拳
Zeus corners Atom, going double duty with both fists!
全民注目  时间所剩无几
Downtown, uptown, as the clock winds down!
-抬手  收下巴  -身体放低  放低
- Hands up, chin down. - Stay low, stay low!
只剩下五秒钟了
Only five seconds left, as
仿佛能听见冠军的脚步渐渐走近
here comes that piston-packed right of the champ!
铃声响了  难以置信
There's the bell! I don't believe it.
阿童木逃过一劫
Somehow Atom has survived.
我们还有第二回合
We will have a second round.
观众们群情激昂
And the crowd here is thrilled!
他成功了  到台角来
He made it! Yeah! Corner!
我们赶快逃  快点
We got to get out of here. We got to get out of here now!
从那儿走  快
We got to go this way. Come on!
好吧  坐下
OK, you sit down.
-我们走吧  老乡  -好吧
- Let's go, homey. - All right.
我会去找你的  宝贝
I'll be back for you, baby.
把手拿开
Get your hands off me!
双方积极修整各自的拳手
Both corners furiously working on their bots.
观众本来期待的是一场屠杀
This crowd came here tonight expecting a massacre,
结果却是一场鏖战
but instead they're getting a war!
-好了吗  -好了
- You got it? - Yeah.
那我们下去
All right. Here we go.
怎么回事
What is happening?
所有最坏的情况
He is fully prepared for
都在我们的掌握之中  他没事的
all possible contingencies. He will be fine.
下一步呢
What next?
第二回合
Round two.
次回合打响  表现优秀的挑战者  阿童木
Round two kicks off, and incredibly the challenger, Atom,
准备与卫冕冠军决一死战
is giving the champ a run for his money.
宙斯一个抱摔把小个子轻松得扔了出去
Zeus tosses the smaller bot across the ring like a tin can!
肯顿指挥着他的拳手
Kenton working his bot with a
以三记右直拳把拳王逼上绝路
trifecta of straight rights to the champ's dome!
第三回合
他们针尖对麦芒  杀得是难分难解
Toe-to-toe they stand, trading deafening blows!
无论双方赛前有多周密的安排
Whatever strategy either corner had
到这时已全然无用武之地
cooked up has been destroyed!
铁臂挥舞  钢拳翻飞
Metal bashing metal. Steel smashing steel.
好一场精彩大战
This is a brawl!
观众们站了起来
The crowd is on their feet,
欣赏着双方欲置对方于死地的厮杀
watching two machines driven to kill each other!
两虎相争必有一伤  没错
Something has to give, and it does!
阿童木再次被击倒
Atom goes down again!
灭灯向垃圾犬致敬
Lights out for the junkyard
感谢他奉献了一场精彩的比赛
dog who put on a heck of a show here tonight!
再次地  阿童木站了起来
And yet again, Atom rises up.
肯顿这次必须展示他的硬实力才行了
Kenton must have hardwired this bot with the will to go on!
第四回合
已经到了第四回合
Midway through round four,
宙斯现在寻找机会要痛下杀手了
and Zeus is looking to end this thing right now.
为了置对方于死地
The champ is holding nothing
拳王展开了狂风骤雨般的攻击
back as he cracks open the hurt locker!
阿童木摇摇欲坠
Atom is stumbling around the ring,
显然已被打懵了
apparently disoriented and dazed!
-抬手  -怎么回事啊
- Hands up! - What's going on?
我想语音识别器挂了  他没反应
I think the voice recog is shot! He's not responding!
宙斯找到了另路攻击手段
Zeus has found yet another gear of violence,
直击阿童木的小腹
drilling Atom's midsection.
不  别打了  想点办法啊
No! Stop! Do something!
他什么也听不见
He can't hear me!
铃声响了  这个小个子
But the bell sounds, and once
再次令全世界为之惊奇
again this little robot has stunned the world!
我们完了  麦克斯
We're done, Max!
他完全接收不到我的指令
He can't hear me.
这是谋杀  我们受够了
This is murder. We've had enough.
我把语音识别功能卸载了
I'm disabling the voice recognition.
有什么用  他又听不见我的指令
For what, he can't hear me!
-但是他看得见  -什么
- Yes, but he can see you! - What?
我把他设为模仿模式  你做给他看
I'm putting him in shadow mode. Show him what to do.
没有语音识别器  他动作可以更快
Without the voice recognition, he'll move even faster!
没门  没门
No way. No way!
瞧瞧他们  他们吓坏了
Look at them. They are freaking out!
富家女要他重新组装一个新的
Rich girl is ripping him a new one over there!
知道为什么吗  因为他们害怕了
Do you know why? Because they're scared.
因为阿童木做到的事  其他任何机器人做不来
Because Atom can do things no other bot has ever done.
-但是我做不了  -不  你做的到
- But I can't do it! - Yes, you can.
-我做不了  -你做得到
- I can't. - Yes, you can.
你做给他看  最后一回合就看你的了
Show him what to do. You have to fight the last round.
别要求我做  不要
Don't ask me. Don't.
查理  拜托  我求你了
Charlie... please. I beg you.
你又来无辜眼神那一套吗
Are you kidding me with those eyes?
妈的
Damn it!
好耶
Yes!
真不敢相信我会这么做
I can't believe I'm doing this.
我知道你在听
I know you're in there!
我不知道你能否听得到
I'm not sure if you're getting this or what,
但我知道你在听
but I know you're in there!
-肯顿  打还是不打  -打  等一下
- Kenton. In or out? - In. Give me a minute.
我知道你听不见
I know you can't hear me,
但你能看见我  那看好了
but you can see me, so watch me!
看  我
Watch... me.
你在和一个机器人说话
You know you're talking to a robot.
我知道  闭嘴
I know. Shut up.
好好看我
Watch me.
今晚这场久违的大战
An epic battle being waged here tonight,
马上就要进入最后一回合的较量了
as the fifth and final round gets underway.
加油  阿童木
Come on, Atom!
等等  你看到了吗
Wait a second. Are you seeing this?
查理·肯顿在外面用模仿模式操控拳手
Charlie Kenton is shadowboxing just outside the ring!
貌似阿童木有个模仿功能
It looks like Atom has a shadow function.
所以  基本上可以说
So, basically, that means Charlie Kenton
最后一回合是查理·肯顿在对抗宙斯
is fighting the last round of this fight against Zeus.
看起来没什么用
It doesn't seem to help,
因为阿童木再次被逼到了台子边缘
because Atom is backed up against the ropes again.
帮帮他  反击啊
Help him! Fight back!
还早
Not yet.
达克·马西多亲自在一旁监视着宙斯的一举一动
Tak Mashido supervising personally as Zeus hammers down,
焦急地等待着能够一劳永逸的除去后患
furiously trying to end this thing once and for all.
我必须要讲  伙计们  冠军体力不支了
I got to tell you, folks, the champ looks tired.
这个机器人好像能量用尽了
This robot seems to be running on empty.
难以置信  阿童木在挑衅宙斯
I don't believe it. Atom is taunting Zeus.
-打开涡轮  -他在让他更使劲的打他
- Switch to turbo! - He's actually asking for more.
赶快还击啊
Please do something!
-不忙  -对  查理  不着急
- Not yet. - That's right, Charlie. Not yet.
液氮加速  开始
Nitrous pistons, now!
他已经撑不了多久了
He's not going to last much longer!
-还击  -还没到时候
- Fight back! - Not yet.
挺住啊
Hang in there!
阿童木正被宙斯充满液氮
Atom is riddled with the
犹如加特林机枪的铁拳打得满目疮痍
nitrous-fueled Gatling guns of Zeus's blows!
阿童木  阿童木  阿童木  阿童木
Atom! Atom! Atom! Atom!
等等  等等  不忙
Wait him out, wait him out! Not yet!
宙斯慢慢停了下来
Zeus is slowing down!
拳王的源动力正在慢慢衰竭
The champ's power core is clearly depleted.
查理  求你了
Charlie, please!
喂  孩子
Hey, kid.
-是时候了  -是时候了
- Now. - Now!
加把劲
Get in there!
锤他狗娘养的  劈成两半
Knock that little bitch! Bust him open!
好  就这样
Yeah! That's right!
别傻呆着
Do something!
滚开
Move!
自动停止  改为手动
Override. Switching to manual.
吃惊的是  达克·马西多
In a shocking move, Tak Mashido
竟然亲自操控他的机器人了
is manually operating his robot personally!
瞄准身体  贴身进攻
Work the body! Get inside him!
揍他  阿童木
Get him, Atom!
看那  拳王
Look at this! The champ
站都站不稳了
is trying desperately to stay on his feet,
而肯顿没有丝毫停顿
but Kenton is relentless,
一波又一波的铁拳击了出去
landing blow after blow after blow to the body!
左  右  左  右
Left! Right! Left! Right!
阿童木一记凶猛的左勾拳
A huge uppercut by Atom!
宙斯轰然倒下
Zeus is down!
这个小个子今晚表现强劲
This little bot has dug deep here tonight
其顽强的精神令人感动
and shown something damn near heart!
一  二  三
One, two, three,
四  五  六  七
four, five, six, seven...
还不错
He's good!
宙斯站了起来
Zeus gets to his feet,
但是阿童木再次向他猛击
but Kenton has Atom on him again,
像雨点般落在他身上
landing punch after punch!
达克·马西多和他的拳王毫无还手之力
Tak Mashido and his super bot have no answer.
宙斯夹住了阿童木的左臂  但肯顿毫不畏惧
Zeus pins Atom's left arm, but Kenton is undaunted!
大局已定  伙计们
It all comes down to this, folks!
干翻他  查理  马上
Drop him, Charlie! Now!
-肯顿准备摔倒拳王  -不  铃声响了
- Kenton is about to drop the champ... - No! There's the bell!
宙斯逃过一劫
Zeus is saved by the bell!
好戏没完  下面将公布裁判的判决
Amazingly, we will go to the judges' cards!
女士们先生们  在五个回合后
Ladies and gentlemen, after five rounds,
现在公布裁判的评分结果
we go to the judges' scorecards.
一号裁判结果是47比48
Judge Number One scores the fight 47-48.
二号裁判结果是48比46
Judge Number Two scores the fight 48-46.
三号裁判结果是47比46
And Judge Number Three scores the fight 47-46,
本场获胜者依然是世界机器人拳王
for the winner and still World Robot Boxing champion,
宙斯
Zeus!
法勒·拉莫科娃
Farra Lemkova,
今晚你们比预期付出的要多
you got way more than you bargained for tonight.
有人说你们赢了比分却输了比赛
Some would say that your bot won the decision but lost the fight.
她气疯了
She looks pissed.
虽然比我们设想的要艰难些
It took a little longer than we thought,
但是结果在预料之中
but the result is as expected.
我们赢了  宙斯仍旧是不可战胜的
We won. Zeus is still undefeated.
达克·马西多
Tak Mashido
你对今晚你的拳王遭受的羞辱
Any comment on the absolutely humiliating near loss
有何看法
your bot suffered tonight?
-不说话  -无可奉告
- Nothing. - No comment.
麦克斯  麦克斯在哪儿
Max. Where's Max?
在这儿  麦克斯
There he is. Max.
已经有人管你的机器人叫"大众拳王"了
They're already calling your bot "The people's champion."
你有什么要说的
What do you say to that?
大众拳王吗
People's champion?
听起来还不错
Sounds pretty good to me.
爸  爸
Dad? Dad!
爸
Dad!
我真的想让你知道
I really want you to know...
不  你必须知道
No, I need you to know.
别担心
Don't worry.
我会守口如瓶
Your secret's safe with me.
等等  等等
Wait here. Wait here.
万岁
Yes!
铁甲钢拳